<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="teibp.xsl"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:lang="en">
    <teiHeader>
        <fileDesc>
            <titleStmt>
                <title>U.S.A and Others v. Araki and Others</title>
                <author>Webb</author>
            </titleStmt>
            <publicationStmt>
                <!-- to be filled in with detail -->
                <p/>
            </publicationStmt>
            <notesStmt>
                <note type="ns">http://www.example.org/ns/nonTEI</note>
            </notesStmt>
            <sourceDesc>
                <!-- original holder be filled in with detail from Yuma -->
                <p>Transcribed from microfilm copy held by</p>
            </sourceDesc>
        </fileDesc>
        <encodingDesc>
            <schemaSpec ident="WebbDraft" docLang="en" prefix="tei_" xml:lang="en">
                <moduleRef key="core" except=""/>
                <moduleRef key="tei" except=""/>
                <moduleRef key="header" except=""/>
                <moduleRef key="textstructure" except=""/>
                <moduleRef key="msdescription" except=""/>
                <moduleRef key="namesdates" except=""/>
            </schemaSpec>
        </encodingDesc>
        <revisionDesc>
            <change><date>3/4/21</date><name>David Gustavsen</name>Created TEI Header and
                notes</change>
        </revisionDesc>
    </teiHeader>

    <text>

        <front>
            <divGen type="toc"/>
        </front>
        <body>
            <div type="part" n="5">
                <pb n="238"/>
                <head><hi rend="underline" rendition="allcaps">Part V - Conventional War Crimes and
                        Crimes Against Humanity Non-Ratification of Geneva Prisoners of War (POW)
                        Convention of 1929</hi></head>
                <p>Japan signed the Geneva POW Convention of 1929 but did not ratify it because the
                    Army and Navy opposed ratification on the grounds that the obligations would be
                    unilateral, since no Japanese would be taken prisoner; the article permitting
                    interviews with prisoners without observers would endanger military security;
                    the treaty would double the range of enemy aircraft if pilots knew they could
                    land in Japan with impunity; and discipline would suffer as Prisoners of War
                    (hereafter called POW) could not be punished as severely as Japanese
                    soldiers.</p>
                <p>The Geneva Convention of 1929 merely confirmed and amplified the Hague Convention
                    of 1899.</p>
                <p rend="centered"><hi rend="underline">Assurances by Japan</hi></p>
                <p>Both Britain and the USA notified Japan that they would observe the Geneva POW
                    Convention of 1929 and the racial customs of POW with regard to food and
                    clothing. After consulting the War Minister, <persName>Foreign Minister
                        TOGO</persName> notified the Protecting Powers that although not bound by
                    the Geneva POW Convention of 1929 Japan “would apply <hi rend="underline"
                        >mutatis mutandis</hi> the provisions of the said Convention”. </p>
                <p>Japan also notified that she would consider on condition of reciprocity the
                    national and racial customs of the prisoners as to food and clothing, and on
                        <date when-iso="1942-02-13"> 13th February 1942</date> advised that the
                    Geneva POW Convention of 1929 would be applied to civilian internees so far as
                    it was applicable.</p>
                <p>
                    <persName>TOGO</persName> testified that he took the phrase “<hi
                        rend="underline">mutatis mutandis</hi>” to mean “as far as circumstances
                    permitted, and that where the Convention conflicted with domestic law the former
                    would prevail.” However, replies to <pb n="239"/> Allied protests showed that
                    this was altered to mean that the convention would be applied only where it did
                    not conflict with Japanese domestic law, and according to a reply of the
                    Japanese Foreign Ministry dated <date when-iso="1944-04-28">28th April
                        1944</date> it was to be applied “with the modifications necessary in order
                    to conform with the provisions of existing laws and regulations of the country
                    and with the requirements of the actual situation as it develops.” </p>
                <p rend="centered"><hi rend="underline">The Japanese Government's Knowledge of War
                        Crimes The Rape of Nanking</hi></p>
                <p>When Nanking fell on <date when-iso="1937-12-13">13th December 1937</date> all
                    Chinese resistance ceased. During the first few days over 30,000 Chinese were
                    executed. Estimates of the number killed in the first 6 weeks vary from 260,000
                    to 300,000. There were 20,000 cases of rape.</p>
                <p> Records show that over 155,000 bodies were buried. Protests sent to the Foreign
                    Ministry were discussed with War Ministry officials at Liaison Conferences.
                    Reports of more than 70 cases of rape were sent to <persName>Foreign Minister
                        HIROTA</persName>. Newspaper reports of the atrocities were referred to in
                    the Budget Committee of the House of Peers on <date when-iso="1938-02-16">16th
                        February 1938</date>.</p>
                <p rend="centered"><hi rend="underline">Knowledge After Nanking and Before Pacific
                        War</hi></p>
                <p> Following the Japanese entry into <location>
                        <placeName>Hankow</placeName>
                    </location> in <date when-iso="1938-10">October 1938</date> captured Chinese
                    were kicked into the Yangtze and shot and some Chinese were left in the streets
                    with their hands wired behind them. All had been killed by shooting. </p>
                <p> On <date when-iso="1939-02-15">15th February 1939</date> the Vice-War Minister
                    issued an order that men returning from the Chinese Incident Army be properly
                    controlled so that they should not talk about atrocities. </p>
                <pb n="240"/>
                <p rend="centered"><hi rend="underline">Knowledge During the Pacific War</hi></p>
                <p> Most protests concerned POW held by the Army. Copies were sent to all Sections
                    of the War Ministry and to other departments, e.g., Navy, Home Affairs, and
                    Justice, depending on the nature of the protest. These were discussed at the
                    bi-weekly conference between the Minister, Vice Minister, and Bureau Chiefs.
                    Afterwards they were forwarded through the POW Information Bureau to the Army
                    Commander and Chief of POW camps. When information was received from them a
                    reply was prepared in the Military Affairs Section of the Military Affairs
                    Bureau and forwarded to the Foreign Office. This system ensured that information
                    of atrocities should be well circulated through the Government offices. </p>
                <p rend="centered"><hi rend="underline">Rangoon</hi></p>
                <p> On <date when-iso="1942-07-08">8th July 1942</date> the Swiss Minister forwarded
                    to <persName>TOGO</persName>, the Foreign Minister, a proteset accompanied by a
                    photograph from a Japanese newspaper of British POW cleaning the streets of
                    Rangoon before amused Burmese onlookers. No reply was received although a
                    reminder was sent. </p>
                <p> A complaint made on <date when-iso="1942-09-15">15th September 1942</date> as to
                    ill treatment and starvation of POW at <location>
                        <placeName>Rangoon Gaol Camp</placeName>
                    </location> met with denial and further protests on <date when-iso="1943-02-12"
                        >12th February 1943</date> and <date when-iso="1944-11-18">18th November
                        1944</date> elicited no response.</p>
                <p rend="centered"><hi rend="underline">Burma Thailand Railway</hi></p>
                <p> From <date when-iso="1942-08">August 1942</date> onwards POW were employed on
                    building a line from <location>
                        <placeName>Kanchananburi in Thailand</placeName>
                    </location> to <location>
                        <placeName>Thanbyuzayat in Burma</placeName>
                    </location>, a distance of about 400 kilos. Of about 46,000 POW so employed
                    16,000 died in eighteen months. In addition about 100,000 to 150,000 natives
                    were employed of whom 60,000 to 100,000 died. This <pb n="241"/> railway was
                    constructed for strategic purposes and the hastening of its completion in <date
                        when-iso="1943">1943</date> greatly increased the death rate. POW were
                    divided into forces distinguished by letters of the alphabet. </p>
                <p> "F" force had 7,000 POW, and 250 Japanese and 30 Korean guards. Of these 3,100
                    POW died in 3 months but only one of the guards. "A" force had 900 deaths among
                    POW but only 4 among the guards. "H" force of 3,000 lost 900 POW in 3
                    months.</p>
                <p> The decision to construct this railway was made by Imperial General Headquarters
                    after a request from Southern Army HQ. It was completed in <date
                        when-iso="1943-10">October 1943.</date></p>
                <p> On <date when-iso="1943-07-05"> 5th July 1943</date> the first Thailand protest
                    relating to British POW was lodged with the accused
                        <persName>SHIGEMITSU</persName> replied on <date when-iso="1943-07-24">24th
                        July</date> that all POW were equitably treated and that the sick received
                    proper medical attention. </p>
                <p> On <date when-iso="1943-08-30">30th August</date> a further protest was lodged
                    and permission sought for the Swiss Consul at Bangkok to visit the camps, but
                        <persName>SHIGEMITSU</persName> replied on <date when-iso="1943-10-01">1st
                        October 1943</date> that POW in Thailand received the same treatment as
                    Japanese troops.</p>
                <p> Southern Army HQ had been advised in 1942, before the railway work was started,
                    that there was grave danger of the prisoners' contracting diseases, and, at the
                    end of 1942, of the growing death rate. On Japanese figures the death rate
                    jumped from 54 in <date when-iso="1942-11">November 1942</date> to 800 in <date
                        when-iso="1943-08">August 1943</date>, total deaths being 2909.</p>
                <p>
                    <persName>WAKAMATSU</persName> of the General Staff inspected <location>
                        <placeName>Burma</placeName>
                    </location> and <location>
                        <placeName>Thailand</placeName>
                    </location> in 1943 as a result of reports that work was being delayed by the
                    poor physical condition of and <pb n="242"/> high death rate among the POW. He
                    reported in <date when-iso="1943-10">October 1943</date> to the General Staff on
                    the diseases he had seen and of the deficiency of the food both in quality and
                    quantity. </p>
                <p> A regular monthly report of the POW Commandant in Thailand made on <date
                        when-iso="1943-09-03">3rd September 1943</date> showed that of 40,314 POW,
                    15,064 were sick.</p>
                <p>On <date when-iso="1944-06-23">23rd June 1944</date> the International Red Cross
                    Chairman proposed to the Japanese Foreign Minister that owing to sickness among
                    POW working on the railway they be repatriated in accordance with the Geneva POW
                    Convention, and that in the meantime the Red Cross would furnish medical
                    supplies if Japan would arrange for their transportation and distribution. On
                        <date when-iso="1944-07-11">11th July 1944</date> the Foreign Office sent
                    copies of this to the War and Navy Ministers and the POW Information Bureau, and
                    information was sought from Southern Army HQ, but nothing was done to give
                    effect to the recommendation.</p>
                <p rend="centered"><hi rend="underline">Wake Island</hi></p>
                <p> Between <date when-iso="1942-04">April 1942</date> and <date when-iso="1945-07"
                        >July 1945</date> the Swiss Minister sent 14 requests for information as to
                    the fate of Americans captured on <location>
                        <placeName>Wake Island</placeName>
                    </location>. Only 3 replies were received, none of which contained any useful
                    information; the fate of all except 173 had to be ascertained from other
                    sources. 96 of the prisoners were executed on <date when-iso="1943-10-07">7th
                        October 1943</date>, and the sole survivor a week later by the admiral in
                    command of the Island. Although the Japanese Government knew that prisoners were
                    detained on the island as labourers it refused to supply the information to the
                    protecting power.</p>
                <p rend="centered"><hi rend="underline">Japan</hi></p>
                <p> On <date when-iso="1943-06-16">16th June 1943</date> the Swiss Minister
                    suggested <pb n="243"/> additional soya products to supplement the prisoners'
                    food in <location>
                        <placeName>Japan</placeName>
                    </location>. On <date when-iso="1943-06-23">23rd June</date> the Foreign
                    Minister replied that there was no necessity for this; yet the War Ministry knew
                    that POW in the <location>
                        <placeName>Tokyo camps </placeName>
                    </location> were dying of malnutrition since the report of the Army Medical
                    College investigation, completed in May 1943, disclosed that prisoners were
                    undernourished.</p>
                <p rend="centered"><hi rend="underline">Dutch Hospital Ship, "Op Ten Noort"</hi></p>
                <p> Protests regarding the seizure and use by the Japanese of the Dutch Hospital
                    Ship "Op Ten Noort" elicited the reply that its capture was justified as the
                    ship was being used for military purposes. No reply was received to further
                    protests that at the time of capture the ship was not being so used; nor was any
                    evidence on this matter brought before the Tribunal.</p>
                <p rend="centered"><hi rend="underline">Philippines and China</hi></p>
                <p> On <date when-iso="1942-12-23">23rd December 1942</date> the Swiss Minister
                    protested on behalf of the USA against ill treatment of POW and internees in the
                    Philippines and China, quoting specific incidents of torture, starvation and
                    murder. After a reminder had been sent replies dated <date when-iso="1944-04-24"
                        >24th</date> and <date when-iso="1944-04-28">28th April 1944</date> either
                    denied the charges or attempted justification.</p>
                <p> These complaints related to the <location>
                        <placeName>Bridgehouse, Shanghai</placeName>
                    </location>, where 53 American prisoners were crowded into vermin-infested cells
                    with inadequate food, heat, medical and sanitary facilities. The reply was that
                    the persons referred to had violated military regulations and were consequently
                    criminals and treated as such.</p>
                <p rend="centered"><hi rend="underline">Bataan Death March</hi></p>
                <p>65,000 American and Filipino POW were kicked and beaten by guards on a nine days'
                    march over 120 kilometers. <persName>Major-General King</persName>, Commanding
                    General of the U.S. Forces <pb n="244"/> at Bataan testified that in destroying
                    equipment prior to surrender he reserved enough motor transporation and gasoline
                    to transport all troops out of Bataan, and asked for this transport, but was
                    told that could not be considered.</p>
                <p>The Japanese reply to protests admits the march but attributed it to lack of
                    transport and denied ill treatment.</p>
                <p rend="centered"><hi rend="underline">Camp O'Donnell</hi></p>
                <p> Replies to protests that 2,200 Americans and 20,000 Filipinos died from lack of
                    medical care did not deny the figures but stated that the inadequacy of medical
                    supplies was due to the fact that the Americans had destroyed their own before
                    capture.</p>
                <p> Despite the knowledge of the Japanese Government similar conditions existed in
                    the <location>
                        <placeName>Philippines</placeName>
                    </location> and <location>
                        <placeName>Shanghai</placeName>
                    </location> until Japan's defeat.</p>
                <p rend="centered"><hi rend="underline">Murder of Crews of Sunken Merchant
                        Ships</hi></p>
                <p> 8 British, American and Dutch merchant vessels were sunk by Japanese submarines
                    in the Indian Ocean between <date when-iso="1943-12-14">14th December
                        1943</date> and <date when-iso="1944-10-29">29th October 1944</date> and one
                    American vessel was sunk in the Pacific Ocean. The submarine in each case took
                    or attempted to take the master of the ship on board and then murdered or
                    attempted to murder the crews.</p>
                <p> On <date when-iso="1944-06-05">5th June 1944</date> the Swiss Minister protested
                    to <persName>SHIGEMITSU</persName> against the treatment of the masters and
                    crews, and in November the Japanese Foreign Office denied the alleged
                    atrocities. In <date when-iso="1945-05">May 1945</date> in reiterating the
                    protest the Swiss Minister quoted an operation order dated <date
                        when-iso="1943-03-20">20th March 1943</date> issued by the Admiral
                    commanding the First Submarine Force which authorized the complete destruction
                        <pb n="245"/> of the crews of sunken vessels except those needed for
                    intelligence. </p>
                <p rend="centered"><hi rend="underline">SS Richard Hovey</hi></p>
                <p> On <date when-iso="1944-06-19">19th June 1944</date> the Swiss Minister
                    protested that when the American vessel "Richard Hovey" was torpedoed the
                    Japanese submarine rammed and then fired on the ship's boats. On <date
                        when-iso="1944-11-28">28th November 1944</date>
                    <persName>SHIGEMITSU</persName> denied these atrocities.</p>
                <p rend="centered"><hi rend="underline">SS Jean Nicolet</hi></p>
                <p> In a protest on 29th December 1944 against the manner of sinking the SS Jean
                    Nicolet the Swiss Minister alleged that lifeboats were rammed and machine
                    gunned; any survivors were taken aboard the submarine where they were robbed of
                    life belts, papers, and valuables and bound in a sitting position on the deck;
                    about half were made to run between rows of Japanese armed with bayonets and
                    rifle butts and then forced off the stern onto the propellers: the submarine
                    submerged while a large number of survivors were still on deck; the Captain and
                    Chief Mate were taken below. </p>
                <p> The Japanese reply of 15th May 1945 denied those allegations.</p>
                <p rend="centered"><hi rend="underline">German and Japanese Policy to Murder Ships'
                        Crews</hi></p>
                <p> In a conversation with <persName>OSHIMA</persName> on <date
                        when-iso="1942-01-03">3rd January 1942</date>, <persName>Hitler</persName>
                    pointed out that America was short of crews for her shipping, and that as many
                    of the crews as possible should be killed. Moreover, the effect on morale and
                    recruiting had also to be considered, and he had given orders that foreign
                    seamen were not to be taken prisoner and submarines were to shoot up the
                    lifeboats. OSHIMA agreed and said that the Japanese were forced to follow
                    similar methods.</p>
                <pb n="246"/>
                <p> On <date when-iso="1943-03-20">20th March 1943</date> the operation order of the
                    First Submarine Fleet instructed submarine commanders to destroy the crews of
                    sunken ships after taking such members into custody as might be useful for
                    intelligence.</p>
                <p rend="centered"><hi rend="underline">Recordings of Broadcasts</hi></p>
                <p>On <date when-iso="1944-01-24">24th January 1944</date> a BBC London Broadcast
                    gave full details of Japanese atrocities committed on American and Filipino
                    prisoners, and on the same day the U.S. Secretary of State broadcast from San
                    Francisco. These and other broadcasts were repeatedly made. On <date
                        when-iso="1944-10-23">23rd October 1944</date> a warning was addressed to
                        <persName>Field Marshal Terauchi</persName> by <persName>General
                        MacArthur</persName> that he would hold enemy leaders responsible for the
                    treatement meted out to prisoners. Transcripts of recordings of these broadcasts
                    were circulated throughout the Foreign Office, the Board of Information and the
                    War and Navy Ministries.</p>
                <p rend="centered"><hi rend="underline">Official Japanese Documents Authorizing or
                        Recording War Crimes</hi></p>
                <p> Japanese official documents show that the Japanese Government compelled POW to
                    engage in military labour.</p>
                <p> (i) In a letter dated <date when-iso="1942-05-06">6th May 1942</date> to the
                    Chief of Staff of the Taiwan Army, <persName>KIMURA</persName>, Vice Minister of
                    War, authorized the confinement of white POW in <location>
                        <placeName>Korea</placeName>
                    </location>, <location>
                        <placeName>Formosa</placeName>
                    </location> and <location>
                        <placeName>Manchuria</placeName>
                    </location> "so that they can be used for the enlargement of our production and
                    as military labour".</p>
                <p> (ii) A Secret Service Police report for <date when-iso="1942-08">August
                        1942</date> mentioned that 150 American POW from <location>
                        <placeName>Zentsuji POW camp</placeName>
                    </location>had been sent to <location>
                        <placeName>OSAKA</placeName>
                    </location> to relieve "the labour shortage suffered in the military works".</p>
                <p> (iii) On <date when-iso="1942-08-22">22nd August 1942</date>,
                        <persName>KIMURA</persName>, wrote to the Chief of Staff of the Kwantung
                    Army of a plan to employ <pb n="247"/> 1500 POW on the production of machine
                    tools for munitions.</p>
                <p> (iv) A conference of the Cabinet Planning Board decided on <date
                        when-iso="1942-08-15">15th August 1942</date> to employ POW labour on
                    construction work for national defence.</p>
                <p> (v) On <date when-iso="1942-10-02">2nd October 1942</date> the Chief of Staff of
                    the Eastern District Army requested permission from <persName>TOJO</persName> to
                    employ POW at "Industrial labour for the expansion of productive power" in
                    "Munition factories for expanding production". A draft approval by the War
                    Minister was attached.</p>
                <p> (vi) A report of the governor of Kanagawa dated <date when-iso="1942-10-06">6th
                        October 1942</date> stated the employment of POW labour had facilitated
                    transportation and "will also contribute greatly to the expansion of production,
                    including munitions of war."</p>
                <p> (vii) A report dated <date when-iso="1942-09-04">4th September 1942</date> from
                        <persName>ITAGAKI</persName> Commander of the Korean Army to accused TOJO
                    showed the regulations in Korean POW Camps provided that POW were to be used
                    "according to their skill, age, and physical strength, thereby using them in
                    industrial development and military labour."</p>
                <p rend="centered"><hi rend="underline">Employment of Officer POW</hi></p>
                <p>Article 6 of teh Hague Convention of 1907 and Article 27 of the Geneva POW
                    Convention, 1929, forbid the compulsory employment of officer POW.</p>
                <p> (i) On <date when-iso="1942-06-03">3rd June 1942</date> the Director of the POW
                    custody division sent a circular to army units stating that although it was
                    prohibited to make officer POW work, "it is the policy of the Central
                    Authorities . . . to have them volunteer to work in accordance with their
                    respective status, intelligence, strength, etc."</p>
                <p> (ii) On <date when-iso="1942-09-04">4th September 1942</date>
                    <persName>ITAGAKI</persName>, sent to <persName>TOJO</persName>
                    <pb n="248"/> a copy of regulations in use in Korea. Article 3 read "All
                    prisoners of war including officers shall work. But guide those above warrant
                    officers according to status, ability, and physical strength to work
                    voluntarily. . . . .".</p>
                <p rend="centered"><hi rend="underline">Protection of POW from Insult</hi></p>
                <p> Article 2 of the Geneva POW Convention 1929 requires that POW must at all times
                    be protected, particularly against insults and public curiosity.</p>
                <p> (i) A report of the Governer of Kanagawa Prefecture of <date
                        when-iso="1942-10-06">6th October 1942</date> mentioned how the morale of
                    the local population was raised by seeing POW at labour.</p>
                <p> (ii) On <date when-iso="1942-03-04">4th March 1942</date> the Chief of Staff of
                    the Korean Army requested <persName>KIMURA</persName> to intern 1000 British and
                    1000 American POW in Korea to stamp out the respect of the Koreans for Britain
                    and America.</p>
                <p> On 5th March KIMURA replied that 1000 POW would be sent, but suggested that the
                    buildings proposed to be used for housing the POW were too good.</p>
                <p> (iii) On <date when-iso="1942-03-23">23rd March 1942</date>
                    <persName>ITAGAKI</persName>, Commanding Korean Army, pointed out to TOJO that
                    the plan to intern British and American POW in Korea was aimed at "stamping out
                    any ideas of worship of Britain and America which the greater part of Korea
                    still retains at bottom".</p>
                <p> (iv) On 13th October 1942 the Chief of Staff of the Korean Army reported to
                    KIMURA that a parade of 998 POW through three towns in Korea "was very
                    successful in driving all admiration for the British and Americans out of their
                    minds......."</p>
                <p rend="centered"><hi rend="underline">Compulsory Paroling of POW</hi></p>
                <p> Article II <note>of the Annex</note> of the Hague Convention of 1907 states that
                    a POW cannot be compelled to accept his liberty on parole.</p>
                <pb n="249"/>
                <p> (i) Article 5 of the Japanese "Detailed Regulations for Treatment of Prisoners
                    of War" reads "As soon as prisoners of war have been imprisoned they shall be
                    administered an oath forbidding them from making an escape". Those who did not
                    comply were deemed to have intentions of escaping and placed under strict
                    surveillance.</p>
                <p> Article 10 of the Japanese "Discipline law for POW" provided an minimum penalty
                    of one year's hard labour for those who violated the oath.</p>
                <p> (ii) On <date when-iso="1942-09-01">1st September 1942</date> the Commander of
                    the Taiwan Army in reporting the arrival of POW stated "At first
                        <persName>Lieutenant General Percival</persName> and others refused to make
                    an oath, but finally all but three signed their names. After that they became
                    obedient".</p>
                <p> (iii) The Chief of Staff of the Korean Army reported on <date
                        when-iso="1942-10-13">13th October 1942</date> that immediately after the
                    arrival of POW in Korea the Japanese succeeded in making them all take the
                    oath.</p>
                <p rend="centered"><hi rend="underline">Ill Treatment of POW</hi></p>
                <p> Article 4 of the Hague Convention of 1907 and Article 2 of the Geneva POW
                    Convention of 1929 require that POW will at all times be humanely treated.</p>
                <p> (i) Japanese Censorship Instructions dated <date when-iso="1943-12-20">20th
                        December 1943</date> from the Chief of the Information Bureau of the War
                    Ministry prohibited any reports which might give the impression of cruel
                    treatment of POW as this might give the enemy food for evil propaganda and bring
                    harm to Japanese interned abroad.</p>
                <p> (ii) Only trivial punishments were inflicted on Japanese foudn guilty of
                    offences against POW.</p>
                <pb n="250"/>
                <p rend="centered"><hi rend="underline">Punishment for Escape</hi></p>
                <p> The Hague and Geneva Conventions provide that only disciplinary punishment may
                    be inflicted on POW for escaping, and this consists of arrest for not more than
                    30 days.</p>
                <p> According to Japanese official figures, between <date when-iso="1942-06-02">2d
                        June 1942</date> and <date when-iso="1945-03-03">3d March 1945</date>, 64
                    prisoners were convicted by Court Martial for violation of the non-escape oath
                    and received sentences ranging from one year's imprisonment to death.</p>
                <p> Article 29 of the Hague Convention states, "A person can be considered a spy
                    only when, acting clandestinely or on false pretenses, he obtains or endeavours
                    to obtain information in the zone of operations of a belligerent, with the
                    intention of communicating it to the hostile party."</p>
                <p rend="centered"><hi rend="underline">Oaths Or Agreements Not To Escape</hi></p>
                <p> Coercive methods were adopted to compel prisoners to make the oath or agreement
                    not to escape and the prisoners were not given their liberty after having given
                    the undertaking not to escape.</p>
                <p> At <location>
                        <placeName>Changi Prisoners of War Camp in Singapore</placeName>
                    </location> on <date when-iso="1942-08-31">31st August 1942</date>, all
                    prisoners were ordered to sign a declaration that they would not escape. They
                    refused. On the evening of <date when-iso="1942-09-02">2d September </date>,
                    16,000 prisoners were herded into <location>
                        <placeName>Selarang Barrack Square</placeName>
                    </location>, and kept there without food or latrine facilities for four days at
                    which time the prisoners agreed, under compulsion, to sign the declaration.</p>
                <p> At <location>
                        <placeName>River Valley Road</placeName>
                    </location> and <location>
                        <placeName>Havelock Road Camps</placeName>
                    </location>
                    <persName>Colonel Heath</persName>, who was in command of the prisoners, <pb
                        n="251"/> refused to have them sign the declaration because it was illegal.
                    He was told by the Japanese that any prisoner who failed to sign would be
                    confined in a narrow space and punished until he did. Having learnt what
                    happened at Changi he ordered the prisoners to sign. </p>
                <p> At <location>
                        <placeName>North Point</placeName>
                    </location> and <location>
                        <placeName>Shamshuipo Camp in <sic>Hongkong</sic>
                        </placeName>
                    </location> in <date when-iso="1942-05">May 1942</date>, all prisoners were
                    compelled to swear an affidavit that they would not escape. Some refused and
                    were thereupon imprisoned in <location>
                        <placeName>Stanley Gaol</placeName>
                    </location>.</p>
                <p> Earlier, in <date when-iso="1942-01">January 1942</date>, patients at the <location>
                        <placeName>Bowen Road Hospital</placeName>
                    </location> were taken out and placed in the hot sun under threat to leave them
                    there until all staff and patients had signed.</p>
                <p>Early in <date when-iso="1942-09">September 1942</date>, at <location>
                        <placeName>Sandakan Camp in Borneo</placeName>
                    </location>, the prisoners were ordered to sign. The Commanding Officer,
                        <persName>Lieutenant Colonel Walsh</persName>, said that he would not sign.
                    He was immediately tied up and beaten and a firing party was detailed to execute
                    him. To save his life the prisoners signed the Declaration.</p>
                <p> At <location>
                        <placeName>Tandjong Priok in Java</placeName>
                    </location> an officer was badly beaten with a chain for refusing to sign.
                    Similar treatment was meted out to officers and men at <location>
                        <placeName>Cycle Camp in Batavia</placeName>
                    </location> and they were told that the prisoners would be deprived of all food
                    until they signed.</p>
                <p> In <date when-iso="1942-09">September of 1942</date> at <location>
                        <placeName>Palembang, Batavia</placeName>
                    </location>, because they refused to sign, 650 prisoners were locked up in a
                    small school, the sick were thrown out of the hospital and the senior officers
                    put in solitary confinement. On account of the death of one of the sick, the
                    prisoners signed on the eighth day.</p>
                <pb n="252"/>
                <p> At <location>
                        <placeName>Zentsuji Camp</placeName>
                    </location>, 41 prisoners were kept in confinement from <date
                        when-iso="1942-06-14">14th June 1942</date> until <date
                        when-iso="1942-09-23">23d September 1942</date> for refusing to take the
                    oath and were finally threatened with execution if they persisted.</p>
                <p>
                    <persName>Brigadier Blackburn</persName> refused to sign the non-escape form at <location>
                        <placeName>Karenko Camp in Formosa</placeName>
                    </location>; he was stripped, beaten and kicked and left in a cell overnight
                    without clothes.</p>
                <p rend="centered"><hi rend="underline">Massacres</hi></p>
                <p> The massacres are in three classes: The first committed during the course of, or
                    immediately after the completion of, some military operation.</p>
                <p>The greatest was the rape of Nanking.</p>
                <p> At <location>
                        <placeName>Hongkong</placeName>
                    </location> between the <date when-iso="1941-12-17">17th</date> and <date
                        when-iso="1941-12-25">25th December 1941</date>, the Japanese massacred
                    about 150 Canadians, mostly medical personnel, who had surrendered. At <location>
                        <placeName>St. Stephen's Hospital</placeName>
                    </location> they bayonetted to death or beheaded 70 patients and 25 members of
                    the staff.</p>
                <p> A Japanese force captured 75 Indian troops near <location>
                        <placeName>Ipoh</placeName>
                    </location> on <date when-iso="1941-12-27">27th December 1941</date>, tied them
                    up and bayonetted them to death. A month later they captured and massacred 150
                    Australian and Indian troops at <location>
                        <placeName>Parit Sulong</placeName>
                    </location>.</p>
                <p> In <location>
                        <placeName>Tarakan, Borneo</placeName>
                    </location>, on <date when-iso="1942-01-12">12th January 1942</date>, 245 Dutch
                    prisoners were machine gunned and bayonetted to death, whilst at <location>
                        <placeName>Balikpapan</placeName>
                    </location> on <date when-iso="1942-02-24">24th February 1942</date> the white
                    population of 80 to 100 Europeans was brutally murdered because of the
                    destruction of oil wells and equipment.</p>
                <p> On <date when-iso="1942-02-14">14th</date> and <date when-iso="1942-02-15">15th
                        February 1942</date>, near <location>
                        <placeName>Katong Hospital</placeName>
                    </location> the personnel of an ambulance were captured <pb n="253"/> and
                    killed, and later on the same day troops of the Imperial Guard Division went
                    through the ground floor of the <location>
                        <placeName>Alexandria Hospital, Singapore </placeName>
                    </location>, bayonetting patients as they lay in their beds, and even on the
                    operating table. Members of the staff were also bayonetted. A further massacre
                    on the following day brought up the total of those murdered at the hospital to
                    323.</p>
                <p> Five thousand Chinese were massacred on the <date when-iso="1942-02-22"
                        >22d</date> and <date when-iso="1942-02-23">23d February</date> at <location>
                        <placeName>Singapore</placeName>
                    </location>. Between <date when-iso="1942-03">March</date> and <date
                        when-iso="1942-04">April 1942</date> many thousand Chinese were arrested and
                    executed in <location>
                        <placeName>Johore Province</placeName>
                    </location>.</p>
                <p>At <location>
                        <placeName>Laha on Ambon Island</placeName>
                    </location>, between the <date when-iso="1942-02-01">1st</date> and <date
                        when-iso="1942-02-20">20th of February 1942</date>, over 300 Australian and
                    Dutch prisoners were murdered in four batches by a naval force on the order of
                        <persName>Admiral HATAKEYAMA</persName>.</p>
                <p> In <location>
                        <placeName>New Britain</placeName>
                    </location>, at <location>
                        <placeName>Tol Tol</placeName>
                    </location> and <location>
                        <placeName>Waitavallo</placeName>
                    </location>, in <date when-iso="1942-02">February 1942,</date>, about 160
                    Australians, many wearing brassards of medical personnel, were captured and shot
                    or bayonetted.</p>
                <p> In the same month at <location>
                        <placeName>Banks Island in Sumatra</placeName>
                    </location>, sixty men, some stretcher cases, and 22 Army Nursing Sisters
                    managed to get ashore after their ship had been sunk by bombing. They gave
                    themselves up to the Japanese, who bayonetted the stretcher cases and machine
                    gunned the remainder.</p>
                <p>At <location>
                        <placeName>Bandoeng and Lembang in Java</placeName>
                    </location>, 150 Dutch prisoners of war were murdered early in <date
                        when-iso="1942-03"> March 1942</date>, whilst later in the same month 25
                    people, including women and children, were taken out of the hospital <pb n="254"
                    /> at <location>
                        <placeName>Soebang</placeName>
                    </location> and shot or bayonetted by the Japanese.</p>
                <p> Other massacres took place at <location>
                        <placeName>Tiga Rungu in Sumatra</placeName>
                    </location>, at <location>
                        <placeName>Longnawen in Borneo</placeName>
                    </location> and at <location>
                        <placeName>Milne Bay in New Guinea</placeName>
                    </location>. In <location>
                        <placeName>New Guinea</placeName>
                    </location> a captured Japanese explained that orders had been given to mutilate
                    prisoners to discourage Japanese troops from surrendering for fear of
                    reprisals.</p>
                <p> In <location>
                        <placeName>French Indo-China</placeName>
                    </location> in <date when-iso="1945-03">March 1945</date> over 600 persons --
                    men, women, and children, soldiers and civilians -- were massacred by the 37th
                    Division.</p>
                <p> In none of the above-mentioned cases was any of the victims tried for any
                    offense.</p>
                <p> The second class of massacres was those committed to terrorize the civilian
                    population.</p>
                <p> At <location>
                        <placeName>Palembang</placeName>
                    </location> in <date when-iso="1943-07">July 1943</date> a large number of
                    prisoners of war and civilians was tortured by the Kempei Tai in an effort to
                    discover the parties to a plot to stir up the Ambonese. Failing to get adequate
                    evidence they executed without trial 80 Ambonese.</p>
                <p> Between <date when-iso="1943-07">July 1943</date> and <date when-iso="1944-03"
                        >March 1944</date> approximately 293 persons were executed without trial in <location>
                        <placeName>Java</placeName>
                    </location> on suspiciion of having been engaged in anti-Japanese activities.
                    This was done on the order of the General Officer commanding the Japanese Forces
                    on the island.</p>
                <p> A revolt took place at <location>
                        <placeName>Jesselton, Borneo</placeName>
                    </location>, on <date when-iso="1943-10-10">10th October 1943</date>. Suspecting
                    that Suluks from a number of small islands north of Borneo had taken part in
                    this revolt the Kempei Tai arrrested, tortured and murdered almost the whole of
                    the male population of the these islands. In addition 170 Chinese were executed
                    in connection with this revolt.</p>
                <p> At <location>
                        <placeName>Pontianak</placeName>
                    </location> in <date when-iso="1944-01">January 1944</date>, 1340 Dutch, Chinese
                    and Indonesians were executed for having allegedly <pb n="255"/> conspired
                    against the Japanese. Only 63 were given a trial.</p>
                <p> Other massacres took place at <location>
                        <placeName>Sinkawang in Borneo</placeName>
                    </location>, <location>
                        <placeName>Timor</placeName>
                    </location> and <location>
                        <placeName>Burma</placeName>
                    </location>.</p>
                <p> The third class of massacres are those which were perpetrated in anticipation of
                    a Japanese withdrawal or of an Allied landing.</p>
                <p> The motive was probably that of preventing prisoners from rendering any
                    assistance to the invading force. As early as <date when-iso="1942-10">October
                        1942</date> at <location>
                        <placeName>Tarawa in the Gilbert and Ellice Islands</placeName>
                    </location>, 22 New Zealand prisoners were murdered after an American air
                    raid.</p>
                <p> In <date when-iso="1943-01">January 1943</date>, 527 British prisoners of war
                    had been transported to <location>
                        <placeName>Ballale Island in the Solomons</placeName>
                    </location> to construct an aerodrome. Most of the them died in the next few
                    months. In <date when-iso="1943-04">April</date> the Japanese feared that the
                    Allies would land and in pursuance of previously made plans bayonetted to death
                    the 90 surviving prisoners.</p>
                <p> A few months later the Naval Commander at <location>
                        <placeName>Wake Island</placeName>
                    </location>, <persName>Admiral SAKIBARA</persName>, caused the 97 surviving
                    prisoners of war to be executed because he expected an American landing.</p>
                <p> At <location>
                        <placeName>New Guinea</placeName>
                    </location> 162 Indian prisoners, who were too sick to move, were massacred in
                        <date when-iso="1944-05">May 1944</date> to prevent them from being
                    recovered by advancing Allied forces.</p>
                <p> In various parts of <location>
                        <placeName>Borneo</placeName>
                    </location> 250 to 300 prisoners were executed between <date when-iso="1945-06"
                        >June</date> and <date when-iso="1945-08"/>August 1945 because they were too
                    sick to be withdrawn inland before the anticipated Allied landing.</p>
                <p> At <location>
                        <placeName>Puerto Princessa, Palawan</placeName>
                    </location>, on <date when-iso="1944-12-14">14th December 1944</date>, 141
                    American prisoners of war were murdered. <pb n="256"/> They had been confined in
                    air raid shelters, petrol was poured into the shelters and set alight, and those
                    who endeavored to escape were shot.</p>
                <p> At <location>
                        <placeName>Ocean Island</placeName>
                    </location>, just before the Japanese surrender, they slaughtered the surviving
                    native population of 100. There was one survivor.</p>
                <p rend="centered"><hi rend="underline">Sandakan-Ranau Death March</hi></p>
                <p> In <date when-iso="1945-02">February 1945</date>, 470 prisoners were made to
                    march from <location>
                        <placeName>Sandakan</placeName>
                    </location> to <location>
                        <placeName>Ranau</placeName>
                    </location> in batches of 50 with Japanese guards. Men who dropped out from
                    exhaustion were immediately shot. For three days the only food allotted to 40
                    men was six cucumbers. Many men were lost through being shot by the Japanese
                    when the fell back. Of one party of 50 who started out, 37 reached <location>
                        <placeName>Ranau</placeName>
                    </location>. Of the 470 who left <location>
                        <placeName>Sandakan</placeName>
                    </location> in <date when-iso="1945-02">February 1945</date>, only 6 were alive
                    in <date when-iso="1945-06">June 1945</date>. All of the Japanese were in good
                    physical condition. In <date when-iso="1945-06">June 1945</date> a party of 140
                    arrived from <location>
                        <placeName>Sandakan</placeName>
                    </location>. These were the survivors out of parties totalling over 1800 men.
                    These six escaped from the Japanese.</p>
                <p rend="centered"><hi rend="underline">Threats</hi></p>
                <p> In <date when-iso="1943-06">June 1943</date>, the Commandant of Naval Police at <location>
                        <placeName>Tarakan</placeName>
                    </location> said that in the event of an Allied landing the prisoners would be
                    beheaded. At <location>
                        <placeName>Nicobar Island</placeName>
                    </location> in <date when-iso="1945-07">July 1945</date> the Naval Commander
                    told the internees that if the enemy landed all of the internees would be
                    killed.</p>
                <p>In <location>
                        <placeName>Borneo</placeName>
                    </location> a similar threat was made; whilst at <location>
                        <placeName>Nakompaton Camp in Thailand</placeName>
                    </location>, prisoners were told by one of the Japanese clerks in the Adjutant's
                    office that he had seen a secret order for the killing of <pb n="257"/>
                    prisoners in the event of an Allied landing. Machine gun posts had been set up
                    covering the huts in which the prisoners were housed.</p>
                <p rend="centered"><hi rend="underline">Punishment for Escaping, In Excess of Hague
                        Convention 1907, And The Geneva Convention 1929.</hi></p>
                <p> At <location>
                        <placeName>Guadalcanal</placeName>
                    </location> in <date when-iso="1942-09">September 1942</date>, two recaptured
                    escapees were handed over to the medical officer who dissected them whilst still
                    alive.</p>
                <p> At <location>
                        <placeName>Ballale Island</placeName>
                    </location> a British escapee was executed without trial in <date
                        when-iso="1943-01">January 1943</date>, as guilty of desertion from the
                    Japanese Army. At <location>
                        <placeName>Shanghai</placeName>
                    </location>, in <date when-iso="1942-03">March 1942</date>, an American escaped
                    prisoner was tried for desertion from the Japanese Army and sentenced to 10
                    years' imprisonment.</p>
                <p>In <location>
                        <placeName>Ambon</placeName>
                    </location> in <date when-iso="1942">1942</date> eleven prisoners who were
                    recaptured outside the camp were beaten for periods up to eleven days and then
                    executed, and in <date when-iso="1945">1945</date> two more recaptured prisoners
                    were executed.</p>
                <p> In <location>
                        <placeName>Celebes</placeName>
                    </location> six Dutch prisoners of war who had been recaptured after escaping
                    were beheaded at <location>
                        <placeName>Macassar</placeName>
                    </location> in <date when-iso="1942-09">September 1942</date>, and at <location>
                        <placeName>Teragan</placeName>
                    </location> three Indians were executed for the same reason in <date
                        when-iso="1945">1945</date>.</p>
                <p> Between <date when-iso="1942-04">April</date> and <date when-iso="1942-05">May
                        1942</date> at various places in <location>
                        <placeName>Java</placeName>
                    </location> there were seven separate cases of recaptured prisoners being
                    exectued for escaping, the total number so punished being 24.</p>
                <p> In <location>
                        <placeName>Sumatra</placeName>
                    </location> three escapees were executed at <location>
                        <placeName>Palembang</placeName>
                    </location>, and eight at the <location>
                        <placeName>island of Siberaeft</placeName>
                    </location>.</p>
                <p> At <location>
                        <placeName>Pontianak</placeName>
                    </location>, <location>
                        <placeName>Bandjermasin</placeName>
                    </location>, <location>
                        <placeName>Tarakan</placeName>
                    </location> and <location>
                        <placeName>Ranau</placeName>
                    </location>, all in <location>
                        <placeName>Borneo</placeName>
                    </location>, a total of ten prisoners were executed<pb n="258"/> between <date
                        when-iso="1942-06">June 1942</date> and <date when-iso="1945-03">March
                        1945</date> for escaping.</p>
                <p> Seven recaptured prisoners were executed in <location>
                        <placeName>Burma</placeName>
                    </location>, three in <location>
                        <placeName>Mukden</placeName>
                    </location>, and eight in <location>
                        <placeName>Hongkong</placeName>
                    </location>.</p>
                <p> In addition to the foregoing executions, all without any trial, two British
                    officers were tortured, tried and shot at <location>
                        <placeName>Hongkong</placeName>
                    </location> in <date when-iso="1943-12">December 1943</date> for endeavouring to
                    effect a wholesale escape.</p>
                <p rend="centered"><hi rend="underline">Execution of Allied Airmen</hi></p>
                <p>On <date when-iso="1942-04-18">18th April 1942</date>, American planes commanded
                    by <persName>Colonel Doolittle</persName> raided <location>
                        <placeName>Japan</placeName>
                    </location>. The crews of two planes were captured in <location>
                        <placeName>China</placeName>
                    </location>. Subsequently to capture "Regulations for Punishment of Enemy Air
                    Crew" were on <date when-iso="1942-08-13">13th August 1942</date> made in <location>
                        <placeName>China</placeName>
                    </location> by the accused <persName>HATA</persName>. The crews were tried by
                    Court Martial under these Regulations and sentenced to death. The sentences in
                    respect to five were commuted to life imprisonment. The remaining three were
                    executed. These Regulations had provided a death penalty for bombing, strafing
                    or otherwise attacking civilians or non-military objectives.</p>
                <p>
                    <sic>Exdcutions</sic> were carried out without trial in <location>
                        <placeName>Bougainville</placeName>
                    </location>, <location>
                        <placeName>New Britain</placeName>
                    </location>, <location>
                        <placeName>New Guinea</placeName>
                    </location>, <location>
                        <placeName>Ambon</placeName>
                    </location>, <location>
                        <placeName>Celebes</placeName>
                    </location>, <location>
                        <placeName> Batavia</placeName>
                    </location>, <location>
                        <placeName>Borneo</placeName>
                    </location>, and <location>
                        <placeName>Burma</placeName>
                    </location>. Fifty-six Allied airmen were executed. These territories consist
                    mostly of sparsely populated jungle country. Moreover the populations were
                    friendly to the Allies. In <location>
                        <placeName>New Guinea</placeName>
                    </location> the officer who issued the orders for the execution admitted that he
                    had done so because the planes <pb n="259"/> had bombed his battery.</p>
                <p> In <date when-iso="1944-12">December 1944</date>, three American airmen who had
                    parachuted in aerial combat near <location>
                        <placeName>Hankow</placeName>
                    </location> were marched through the streets, severly beaten, soaked with
                    gasoline and set on fire, and in the <location>
                        <placeName>Philippines</placeName>
                    </location> in <date when-iso="1945-03">March 1945</date>, two American airmen
                    were beheaded at <location>
                        <placeName>Cebu</placeName>
                    </location>.</p>
                <p>In <location>
                        <placeName>Singapore</placeName>
                    </location> two members of the crew of a B-29 which had been shot down were
                    lodged in the <location>
                        <placeName>Outram Road Gaol</placeName>
                    </location> which was under <persName>DOHIHARA</persName>'s control, as
                    Commander of the 7th Area Army. They were a mass of burns and black from head to
                    foot, but received no medical treatment.</p>
                <p>Between <date when-iso="1945-05">May</date> and <date when-iso="1945-07">July
                        1945</date>, when the accused <persName>ITAGAKI</persName> was the Commander
                    of the 7th Area Army, 26 Allied airmen were taken from the <location>
                        <placeName>Outram Road Gaol</placeName>
                    </location> and executed.</p>
                <p> In <location>
                        <placeName>Japan</placeName>
                    </location>, between <date when-iso="1945-06">June</date> and <date
                        when-iso="1945-08">August 1945</date>, 112 airmen were executed and of these
                    99 were not tried.</p>
                <p rend="centered"><hi rend="underline">Treatment of Prisoners of War and
                        Inhabitants by the Kempei Tai</hi></p>
                <p> The tortures which suggest a common training were the water torture, the
                    electric torture, suspending a victim for long periods, burning various parts of
                    the body and placing a pole between the victim's knees and jumping on the
                    victim's thighs. All of these tortures were adminstered by the Kempei Tai at <location>
                        <placeName>Singapore</placeName>
                    </location>, <location>
                        <placeName>Shanghai</placeName>
                    </location>, <location>
                        <placeName>French Indo-China</placeName>
                    </location>, <location>
                        <placeName>Borneo</placeName>
                    </location>, <location>
                        <placeName>Java</placeName>
                    </location> and <location>
                        <placeName>Sumatra</placeName>
                    </location>, while in <location>
                        <placeName>Burma</placeName>
                    </location> and <location>
                        <placeName>Timor</placeName>
                    </location> many were applied. In <location>
                        <placeName>Japan</placeName>
                    </location> there is evidence of the water torture having been applied to the
                    Doolittle Fliers.</p>
                <pb n="260"/>
                <p rend="centered"><hi rend="underline">Transportation of Prisoners of War by
                        Sea</hi></p>
                <p> Evidence shows that in nearly every case there was crowding, underfeeding,
                    inadequate sanitation and ventilation, lack of medical supplies and water, and
                    ill-treatment.</p>
                <p rend="centered"><hi rend="underline">General Matters</hi></p>
                <p> In every installation throughout <location>
                        <placeName>Japan</placeName>
                    </location> and the occupied countries where prisoners of war were held, they
                    were starved, subjected to corporal punishment, and their sick were neglected.
                    Allied prisoners of war were compelled to labor at work having a direct
                    connection with operations of war. For the most part this consisted of the
                    construction of aerodromes and building defences against anticipated attacks by
                    the Allied forces.</p>
                <p rend="centered"><hi rend="underline">Red Cross Visits Prohibited</hi></p>
                <p> Repeated attempts were made by the International Red Cross and the Protecting
                    Powers to obtain permission for their representative to visit POW camps, but
                    these attempts failed almost invariably.</p>
                <p> In <location>
                        <placeName>Singapore</placeName>
                    </location>, the resident International Red Cross Delegate was not permitted to
                    visit any of the camps.</p>
                <p rend="centered"><hi rend="underline">Concealing Guilt</hi></p>
                <p> Official orders issued to destroy documents, and authorizing the escape of
                    guilty persons show that the Japanese Government was well aware of the fact that
                    war crimes had been committed on a large scale.</p>
                <p> Adjutant General under the order of the War Minister on <date
                        when-iso="1945-08-14">14th August 1945</date> issued a notification to all
                    Army <pb n="261"/> troops that "the confidential documents held by every troop
                    should be destroyed by fire immediately" and instructions were issued by the
                    Chief of the Military Police on <date when-iso="1945-08-14">14th August
                        1945</date> ordering the destruction of documents.</p>
                <p> A circular was sent by the Chief of the Prisoner of War Information Bureau to
                    the Korean Army, Taiwan Army, Kwantung Army, North China Army, to Hongkong,
                    Borneo, Thailand, Malaya and Java on <date when-iso="1945-08-20">20th August
                        1945</date>. It stated, "Personnel who ill treated prisoners of war and
                    internees or who are held in extremely bad sentiment by them are permitted to
                    take care of it by immediately transferring or fleeing without trace. Moreover
                    documents which would be unfavorable for us in the hands of the enemy are to be
                    treated in the same way as secret documents and destroyed when finished
                    with."</p>
                <p rend="centered"><hi rend="underline"><del>Conclusiom</del> Common Plan <note>of
                            Atrocities - Conclusion</note></hi></p>
                <p>The war crimes committed by the Japanese armed forces were exceeded in number and
                    hideousness only by these committ<del>t</del>ed by the Germans under Hitler.
                    They were so many and so terrible and raised such a storm of protest throughout
                    the Allied world that they <del>need</del><note>must</note> have been known to
                    all Japanese leaders, and more particularly by the accused. Yet nothing
                    effective was done to prevent them. This fact, and the further fact that these
                    war crimes were of a similar kind throughout the various Japanese prisoner of
                    war camps in <location>
                        <placeName>Japan</placeName>
                    </location> and the territories occupied by her forces suggest a common plan.
                    However they could have been the result of the application in exaggerated form
                    of the dreadful Japanese <pb n="262"/> Army discipline and Kempei Tai and other
                    police methods to Allied prisoners of war and internees.</p>
                <p>Of course, the accused are not excused because the Army and police were the
                    actual perpetrators. Even civilians among the accused, like
                        <persName>TOGO</persName> and <persName>HIROHATA</persName>, were in a
                    position to protest or to appeal to the Emperor, and if necessary, to bring
                    about a crisis in the Japanese government in order to prevent atrocities. The
                    consequences to them <del>are beside the point</del><note>were beside the
                        point</note>. They had to take whatever risks were incurred inteh execution
                    of their clear duty.</p>
                <p> The nature and extent of the atrocities and the volume of unsuccessful protests
                    suggests that the accused must have known what was taking place and at least
                    either acquiesced through fear or otherwise or were indifferent.</p>
                <p>There is no ground for assuming that the Japanese accused would not have
                    permitted these atrocities had they been aware of them and in a position to
                    prevent them. We know from the German atrocities, which were mainly the work of
                    civilians, of what excesses modern war criminals <del>,</del> are capable.
                    Actually the German atrocities vastly exceeded the Japanese in cruelty and
                    number. At <location>
                        <placeName>Breendonck</placeName>
                    </location> internees were tortured by slowly forcing their legs apart until the
                    body split at the crotch. Elsewhere a gorilla-llike man was employed to break
                    the bones of inmates by twisting <pb n="263"/> their arms and legs. Inoculations
                    with pus from diseased persons were performed on 600 to 800 inmates of <location>
                        <placeName>Dachau</placeName>
                    </location>. The persons selected were healthy and free from social diseases.
                    The inoculations led in many cases to general blood-poisoning, intense agony and
                    amputations. As one limb was lopped off another was inoculated until all limbs
                    were amputated. Most of the victims became permanent invalids and were then
                    murdered.</p>
                <p> This was not the work of a few
                    <del>maniacs</del><del><note>sadists</note></del>; it was organized under the
                    government with whom the Japanese made the <note><unclear reason="illegible"/>
                        ,the</note> Anti-Comintern, the Tri-Partite, and the No-Separate-Peace
                    Pacts. Over a million were murdered in gas chambers at <location>
                        <placeName>Harthein</placeName>
                    </location><note>.</note>
                    <del>t</del><note>T</note>he rate of such murders reached twelve thousand a day
                    at <location>
                        <placeName>Auschwitz</placeName>
                    </location> where two and a half million were murdered.</p>
                <p>But those are only one or two examples of the cold-blooded cruelty adn mass
                    destruction of human life by the Germans, who invented these methods.
                        <del>t</del><note>T</note>hey were not a legacy <del>from</del>
                    <note>of</note> a barbaric past.</p>
                <space/>
                <pb n="264-A"/>
                <p> Article 5 (a) of the Tokyo Charter is in the same terms as Article 6 (a) of the
                    Nuremberg Charter. The Nuremberg Tribunal did not regard Article 6 (a) as
                    defining several separate crimes. The Tribunal said at page 54 of its
                    Judgment:</p>
                <p rend="indent">In the opinion of the Tribunal aggresive war <del>in</del>
                    <note>is</note> a crime under international law. The Charter defines this
                    offense as planning, preparation, intitiation, or waging of a war of aggression
                    or participation in a common plan 'or conspiracy for the accomplishment.....of
                    the foregoing.' The indictment follows this distinction. Count one charges the
                    common plan or conspiracy. Count two charges the planning and waging of war. The
                    same evidence has been introduced to support both counts....."</p>
                <p>The Nuremberg Tribunal, having the Pact of Pari<note>s</note> in mind, did not
                    regard the Charter as defining several crimes against peace but regarded it as
                    specifying several ways of <del>committing</del><note><unclear
                            reason="illegible"/>in</note> the same crime, that of aggressive war. In
                    so doing, the Charter merely stated the law as it existed apart from the
                    Charter.</p>
                <p>The prosecution at Nuremberg in drafting the Indictment did not associate
                    planning with conspiracy but with the waging of war. Conspiracy consists of the
                    mere agreement. Planning and preparation for war, like initiating and waging
                    war, may be evidence of <del>a</del>conspiracy but are not elements of it.</p>
                <pb n="264-B"/>
                <p>
                    <del>In construing an indictment in our national courts we have the assistance
                        of special statutory rules and of decisions; but in this international
                        jurisdiction, we have no such assistance <note>,</note> apart from
                        principles of <del>universal</del><note>general</note> application, and so
                        we must take the indictment as we find it and construe it according to the
                        meaning of its language. </del></p>
                <p>
                    <del>Keeping this in mind, if I find an accused guilty of aggressive war by,
                        say, planning <hi rend="underline">and</hi> preparing it, I shall find him
                        guiilty of planning <hi rend="underline">and</hi> preparing under the
                        appropriate count. But I can see no necessity -- as there was at Nuremberg
                        under Count 2 -- for construing the word "and" as distributive and not
                        conjunctive in the phrase "planned and prepared" in Counts 6 to 17
                        inclusive, and so if I find an accused guilty of planning <hi
                            rend="underline">or</hi> preparing, but not of both, I can and shall
                        find him guilty of waging war under the appropriate count.</del></p>
                <p> Notwithstanding the distinction drawn between <note>conspiring,<unclear
                            reason="illegible"/>,</note> initiating and waging war, I think the
                    counts of waging war are not confined to engaging in actual fighting but
                        <del>are broad enough to</del> cover all kinds of waging war not teh subject
                    of special counts, e.g. counseling, procuring, aiding, abetting, etc.</p>
                <p><del> If I find that an accused guilty of initiating or waging aggresive war, I
                        shall find him guilty under the appropriate count.</del></p>
                <p> If I find an accused guilty of participating <pb n="264-C"/> in a common plan or
                    conspiracy I shall find him guilty under the approprate conspiracy count, even
                    if I am satisfied that the object or motive of the conspiracy was not exactly,
                    but was substantially, that alleged in the relevant count. A variance between
                    the evidence and the indictment may, I think, be disregarded if that can be done
                    without prejudice to the rights of the accused.</p>
                <p> But to <note type="circled">completely</note> disregard object or motive as not
                    being <note>an</note> element<del>s</del> of the offence of conspiracy would be
                    to leave the Counts 1 to 5 in the same form and without any difference in the
                    five allegations <note><unclear reason="illegible"/>as to countries</note>. At
                    Nuremberg there was only one count of conspiracy <del>and it was backed
                        by</del><note>supported <del>with</del> by</note> particulars.
                        Th<note>at</note> course avoided difficulties.</p>
                <p> Whil<del>st</del><note>e</note> it will be impossible to avoid finding
                    conspiracy in <del>most if not all</del><note>most <del>if</del></note> cases
                        <note>,</note> the difficulty will be to find what particular conspiracy
                        <note>or conspiracies</note> an accused joined <note>, if there was more
                        than one conspiracy, as I think was the case</note>. Motives or objects are
                    not always easy to <del>unravel</del>
                    <note>discover</note>. Some accused were <del>talkative</del>
                    <note>communicative</note>; but many acted without saying much.</p>
                <p>If we are not satisfied beyond reasonable doubt that an accused had an object or
                    motive substantially of the kind stated in one of the five conspiracy counts we
                    cannot find him guilty of conspiracy under any count, unless we disregard object
                    or motive <note>and</note> find him guilty under all or any of the five counts
                    -- a course I do not intend to follow. If I find an accused guity of conspiring
                    to wage a war which <pb n="264-D"/> eventuated I shall find him guilty of waging
                    it under the appropriate count, if I am not satisfied beyond reasonable doubt of
                    his object or motive <del>of</del><note>and</note> that it corresponded
                    substantially with an object stated in one of the Counts 1 to 5.</p>
            </div>
        </body>
    </text>
</TEI>
