<?xml version="1.0"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:lang="en">
    <teiHeader>
        <fileDesc>
            <titleStmt>
                <title>U.S.A and Others v. Araki and Others</title>
                <author>Webb</author>
            </titleStmt>
            <publicationStmt>
                <!-- to be filled in with detail -->
                <p/>
            </publicationStmt>
            <notesStmt>
                <note type="ns">http://www.example.org/ns/nonTEI</note>
            </notesStmt>
            <sourceDesc>
                <!-- original holder be filled in with detail from Yuma -->
                <p>Transcribed from microfilm copy held by</p>
            </sourceDesc>
        </fileDesc>
        <encodingDesc>
            <schemaSpec ident="WebbDraft" docLang="en" prefix="tei_" xml:lang="en">
                <moduleRef key="core" except=""/>
                <moduleRef key="tei" except=""/>
                <moduleRef key="header" except=""/>
                <moduleRef key="textstructure" except=""/>
                <moduleRef key="msdescription" except=""/>
                <moduleRef key="namesdates" except=""/>
            </schemaSpec>
        </encodingDesc>
        <revisionDesc>
            <change><date>3/4/21</date><name>David Gustavsen</name>Created TEI Header and
                notes</change>
        </revisionDesc>
    </teiHeader>

    <text>

        <front>
            <divGen type="toc"/>
        </front>
        <body>
            <div type="part" n="6d">
            <pb n="497"/>
                <p rend="centered"><hi rend="underline">OKA, Takazumi</hi></p>
                <p><hi rend="underline">Facts found:</hi></p>
                <p><persName>OKA</persName> became Rear Admiral on <date when-iso="1939-12-01">1st December 1939</date> and Vice Admiral on <date when-iso="1942-12-01">1st December 1942</date>. Before that he spent several years on the Naval General Staff and in the Navy Ministry.</p>
                <p>As Chief of Section One, Naval Affairs Bureau, from <date when-iso="1938-01-15">15th January 1938</date>, his duties extended to naval armaments and adminisration, construction and organization of warships, weapons of war and other munitions and guarding and defense.</p>
                <p>As Chief of the Third Division from <date when-iso="1939-10-15">15th October 1939</date> to <date when-iso="1940-10-15">15th October 1940</date>, he had charge of military intelligence, comprising collecting and piecing together information on the international situation, and war preparedness, including war preparedness of the major powers.</p>
                <p>As Chief of the Naval Affairs Bureau after <date when-iso="1940-10-15">15th October 1940</date>, he supervised the activities of the entire Bureau, including Section Two which handled national defense policy and international conventions.</p>
                <p>The Navy Ministry and War Ministry established a liaison through <persName>OKA</persName> of the Naval Affairs Bureau and <persName>MUTO</persName> of the Military Affairs Bureau.</p>
                <p><persName>OKA</persName> was also liaison betweent the Navy and the <pb n="498"/> Diet, Imperial General Headquarters, the Foreign Office, the Imperial and Liaison Conferences.</p>
                <p><hi rend="underline">The Washington Naval Treaty, and Secret Rearming</hi></p>
                <p>From <date when-iso="1932">1932</date> to <date when-iso="1936">1936</date> during which <persName>OKA</persName> was officer in charge of the Naval Disarmament Section, and a member of the Disarmament Delegation to the League of Nations, the Japanese Navy conducted a successful campaign against the Washington Naval Treaty, insisting that Japan must demand parity or a great increase in relative tonnage at the Conference in <date when-iso="1935">1935</date>. By <date when-iso="1933-09">September 1933</date> they had built up a feeling of resentment or contempt for anything or anyone connected with the Treaty. In <date when-iso="1933-10">October 1933</date> the Navy was demanding equality in armaments, and if this demand was denied woudl seek to abrogate the Treaty even at the risk of a rupture. The preliminary Naval Disarmament Conference convened in <date when-iso="1934-06">June 1934</date> but Japan's delegation did not arrive until <date when-iso="1934-10">October</date>. At this Preliminary Conference the Navy advocated the common upper limit and the abrogation of the Treaty. The Foreign Office opposed because it would give rise to doubts as to the peaceful intentions of Japan, but was overruled and the Navy plan was adopted as the basic policy of Japan at the Disarmament Conference.</p>
                <p>On<date when-iso="1934-12-29">29th December 1934</date>Japan gave notice of her intention to withdraw from the Treaty, effective <date when-iso="1936-12-31">31st December 1936</date>. On <date when-iso="1935-08-21">21st August 1935</date> <persName>SHIGEMITSU</persName> told <persName>Harada</persName> that the Navy opposed Britain's plan <pb n="499"/> for qualitative limitation as meaningless without quantitative limitation. The instructions to the Japanese delegation to the London Naval Conference on <date when-iso="1936-01-12">12th January 1936</date> embodied the Navy proposal for a common upper limit in place of the 5-5-3 ratio, which meant that Japan would dominate the Pacific unless Britain and America reduced their naval strength elsewhere.</p>
                <p>On <date when-iso="1936-01-15">15th January 1936</date> the Japanese delegation led by <persName>Admiral NAGANO</persName> withdrew from the London Naval Conference. Then Japan launched a program of naval rearmament, and laid the keels for two battleships and three Navy cruisers, which exceeded the London Naval Treaty limits.</p>
                <p>On <date when-iso="1938-02-12">12th February 1938</date> <persName>Foreign Minister HIROTA</persName> declined <persName>Secretary of State Hull</persName>'s request for assurances that Japan was not constructing or acquiring capital ships or cruisers not in conformity with the London Naval Treaty. <persName>HIROTA</persName> tried to persuade the Navy to agree as the Navy would have to make necessary explanation to the Diet as well as to the Finance Ministry; but the Navy insisted that the maintenance of secrecy was not impossible in Japan. The details of the budgets were in fact kept secret from the Diet.</p>
                <p>This expansion was stated by the Navy at an Imperial General Headquarters Council on <date when-iso="1936-02-18">18th February 1936</date> to be necessary for preparing against <pb n="500"/> Great Britain and America.</p>
                <p><hi rend="underline">Fortification of the Mandated Islands</hi></p>
                <p>Japan secretly fortified the Mandated Islands. The Naval Affairs Bureau played the leading part in rearming them.</p> 
                <p rend="centered"><hi rend="underline">Greater East Asia</hi></p>
                <p>In <date when-iso="1938">1938</date> <persName>OKA</persName> was Secretary of the Bureau of Manchurian Affairs and associated with the Organizing Committee of the North China Development Company, Ltd., and the Central China Develpment Company, Ltd.</p>
                <p>These Development Companies procured war materials for the Japanese hostilities in China and to expand the armaments of Japan.</p>
                <p>In <date when-iso="1939">1939</date> <persName>OKA</persName> was secretary of the Liaison Committee of the China Affairs Board which exercised control over industry, transportation and economic problems of China through these Development Companies.</p>
                <p rend="centered"><hi rend="underline"><persName>OKA</persName>'s Political Activities</hi></p>
                <p>On <date when-iso="1938-07-08">8th July 1938</date> the Five Ministers' Conference decided Japan's whole strength should be concentrated upon bringing about the destruction or surrender of the Central Government of China. To carry out this policy the Conference on <date when-iso="1938-10-07">7th October 1938</date> established the secret Liaison Committee to accelerate the performance of matters agreed upon by the Five Ministers' Conferene and composed of eight members among whom were the Chief of the Naval <pb n="501"/> Affairs Bureau and the Chief of Section One of the Naval Affairs Bureau. Among the four secretaries was the Chief of Section One of the Naval Affairs Bureau. Hence the Naval Affairs Bureau had two members on the committee and one on the secretariat. <persName>OKA</persName>, as Chief of Section One, Naval Affairs Bureau, was both member and secretary.</p>
                <p><persName>OKA</persName> was a councillor of the I.R.A.A.</p>
                <p>In <date when-iso="1941-04">April 1941</date> as Chief of the Naval Affairs Bureau he made a report to <persName>Premier Konoe</persName> concerning the proposal by <persName>Konoe</persName> to have <persName>Vice Navy Minister Toyoda</persName> accept a position in the new Cabinet as Minister of Commerce and Industry to counterbalance the appointment of <persName>Lt. Gen. SUZUKI</persName> as President of the Planning Board.</p>
                <p>An entry in <persName>KIDO</persName>'s Diary for <date when-iso="1944-07-17">17th July 1944</date> shows that <persName>OKA</persName> had attempted to induce <persName>Admiral Yonai</persName> to accept a cabinet position in a last effort to save the Cabinet. In <date when-iso="1944-07">July 1944</date> Navy member <persName>Nomura, <unclear reason="illegible"></unclear></persName> ordered <persName>OKA</persName> to sound out <persName>Yonai</persName> as a prospective cabinet member.</p>
                <p rend="centered"><hi rend="underline">Imperial <unclear reason="illegible"></unclear>Conferences and Privy Council Meetings</hi></p>
                <p><persName>OKA</persName> while Chief of the Naval Affairs Bureau attended the Imperial and Liaison Conferences and <pb n="602"/> Investigation Committee meetings of the Privy Council except three or four when he was ill. From <date when-iso="1941-01">January</date> to <date when-iso="1941-07">July 1941</date> he attended all four Imperial Conferences during <date when-iso="1941">1941</date>, namely, on <date when-iso="1941-07-02">2nd July</date>, <date when-iso="1941-09-06">6th September</date>, <date when-iso="1941-11-05">5th November</date> and <date when-iso="1941-12-01">1st December 1941</date>.</p>
                <p><persName>OKA</persName> with <persName>MUTO</persName> and <persName>Tomita</persName> was present at Imperial Conferences, as a Secretary to give explanations. He attended meetings of the Investigation Committee of the Privy Council, at which the Navy Minister was not present, on <date when-iso="1942-10-21">21st October 1942</date> when the Committee met to consider the establishment of the Greater East Asia Ministry, and on <date when-iso="1943-08-18">18th August 1943</date> when the Committee unanimously approved the draft of the treaty between Japan and Thailand for the annexation of Malay territory by Thailand. <persName>MUTO</persName> and <persName>OKA</persName> as secretaries explained the various plans and proposals submitted and participated in the debates.</p>
               <p>The Liaison Conferences began with the first Konoe Cabinet when it became necessary to establish liaison between the military High Command and the <pb n="503"/> Cabinet. <persName>TOGO</persName> said such conferences were proof that the military were not only interfering in politics but were influencing the control and direction of national policy, and that some coordination was needed; decisions of the Liaison Conference involving affairs of state had to be presented to the Cabinet--and, in proper cases, to an Imperial Conference--but almost invariably the decisions passed through the Cabinet in the form in which the Conference had adopted them; drafts of the decisions of the Liaison Conferences were always prepared beforehand, the matters examined by the staffs of the ministers concerned and coordinated by the three secretaries before they were submitted to the Conference. <persName>MUTO</persName> said that he and <persName>OKA</persName> coordinated the efforts of the Army and Navy and of the Prime Minister and Finance Ministers.</p>
               <p rend="centered"><hi rend="underline">March to the South</hi></p>
               <p>On <date when-iso="1940-07-25">25th July 1940</date> the second Konoye Cabinet defined Japan's basis national policy as the construction of a new order in Greater East Asia built upon the firm solidarity of Japan, Manchukuo and China with Japan as the centre.</p>
               <p>Japan made demands on France for the passage of Japanese troops through the province of <location><placeName>Tongking</placeName></location> in Northern French Indo-China, the use of airfields in <location><placeName>Tongking</placeName></location>, and the stationing of troops and provision for the transportation of arms and <pb n="504"/> ammunition, and intimated that if no immediate reply was received, Japan would resort to force. The French ambassador replied that acceptance of these demands would be the equivalent of a declaration of war by France on China.</p>
               <p>On <date when-iso="1940-09-22">22nd September 1940</date> the Japanese Army attacked the <location><placeName>Tongking</placeName></location> border. The same day the French agreed to the Japanese Army and Navy terms, including the right to station 32,000 troops in <location><placeName>Indo-China</placeName></location> and to anchor one warship in <location><placeName>Haiphong harbor</placeName></location>.</p>
               <p>The Liaison Conference of <date when-iso="1941-01-30">30th January 1941</date>, attended by both <persName>OKA</persName> and <persName>MUTO</persName>, decided the policy toward French Indo-China and Thailand, namely, to establish Japan's leading position in Indo-China and Thailand to prepare for the southward policy. As part of these preparations the Navy contemplated the use of <location><placeName>C<unclear reason="illegible"></unclear>canh Bay</placeName></location> and the air bases near <location><placeName>Saigon</placeName></location>. It was decided to disguise the real purpose as "preservation of trade and communications" and "security against war between Indo-China and Thailand." The decision stated that Japan would resort to arms against French Indo-China if unavoidable.</p>
               <p>On <date when-iso="1941-02-03">3rd February 1941</date> <persName>OKA</persName> and <persName>MUTO</persName> attended the <pb n="505"/> Liaison Conference which made a decision to be used as instructions by <persName>MATSUOKA</persName> in his negotiations with Germany, Italy and the Soviet Union during his European visit. The decision provided that Japan would be the political leader in the Greater East Asia Co-Prosperity Sphere and responsible for the maintenance of order. The people of those areas should, in principle, maintain independence or be made independent; but those in districts then in the possession of Britain, France, Holland, Portugal and others, who were incapable of being independent, were to be permitted to have as much self-government as possible under the guidance of Japan. Economically, Japan would reserve preference over the defense resources of those districts but in other commercial enterprises would adopt the principle of open door and equal opportunity. The world was to be divided into four great blocs including the Greater East Asia bloc under Japan and the European Bloc (including Africa) under Germany.</p>
               <p>In <date when-iso="1941-03">March 1941</date> a report to <persName>Ribbentrop</persName> from <persName>Ott</persName> stated that the Japanese Army was vigorously preparing for an attack on Singapore and was expected to be ready by the end of <date when-iso="1941-05">May</date>. In <date when-iso="1941-04">April 1941</date>, Imperial Headquarters decided measures to be taken in the South and that in certain circumstances it would be necessary to resort to arms. <persName>OKA</persName> was a member of the Department of Naval Preparedness Examination, and an assistant to <pb n="506"/> the Navy Minister in Imperial Headquarters, which had all the secret files.</p>
               <p>In <date when-iso="1941-04">April 1941</date> the Planning Board, when <persName>OKA</persName> was councillor, issued a confidential pamphlet entitled "Outline of Fundamental National Policies" which included a Cabinet plan of <date when-iso="1941-01-22">22nd January 1941</date> relating to the fundamental principles of Japan's population policy. The plan stated that it was the mission of Japan to establish the East Asia Co-Prosperity Sphere and to accomplish this it was necessary to increase the population quickly, enhance its military quality and correct distribution of Japanese emigrants to secure leadership over the races of East Asia.</p>
               <p>The Soviet Union was invaded by Germany on <date when-iso="1941-06-22">22nd June 1941</date>. On <date when-iso="1941-06-25">25th June 1941</date>. On <date when-iso="1941-06-25">25th June</date>, <persName>OKA</persName> and <persName>MUTO</persName> attended a Liaison Conference which decided to that a military union should be established with Indo-China as soon as possible, stressing the establishment or use of air bases and harbor facilities in Indo-China and the stationing of troops in the Southern part. Failing that, it was decided that Japan would attain her objective by force, for which preparations would be made in advance.</p>
               <p>On <date when-iso="1941-07-02">2nd July 1941</date> <persName>OKA</persName> attended the Imperial Conference which decided that Japan should adhere to the principle of establishing a Greater East Asia Co-Prosperity Sphere; step up the Soutward advance; accomplish the execution of the schemes</p> <!-- pages 507-516 are missing from source document--> 
               <pb n="517"/>
               <p>Headquarters in Tokyo; or of the murder of crews and passengers of ships torpedoed by submarines pursuant to the written order No. 2 of <date when-iso="1943-03">March 1943</date>. But he cannot on the evidence be found to have been a party to those orders.</p>
               <p>Guilty under Counts <note>3, 4, 6 to <del><unclear reason="illegible"></unclear></del>18 inclusive, 20-22 inclusive, <del><unclear reason="illegible"></unclear></del>23,</note> 27, 29 to 32 inclusive, 34, and 55.</p>
               <p><note>*not changed?</note></p>
               <pb n="518"/>
               <p rend="centered"><hi rend="underline">OSHIMA, Hiroshi</hi></p>
               <p><persName>Himmler</persName> and other notorious leaders of Germany frequently called upon <persName>Military Attache General OSHIMA</persName> at the <location><placeName>Berlin Embassy</placeName></location>.</p>
               <p rend="centered"><hi rend="underline">Plot to Kill <persName>Generalissimo Stalin</persName></hi></p>
               <p><persName>Himmler</persName> recorded <persName>OSHIMA</persName> as having said on <date when-iso="1939-01-31">31st January 1939</date> that he was undertaking long range work of disintegration of Russia emanating in the Caucasus and the Ukraine, that he had succeeded in sending ten Russians with bombs across the Caucasian frontier with orders to kill <persName>Stalin</persName>; and that six Russians were employed in writing and printing pamphlets at <location><placeName>Falkensee</placeName></location>.</p>
               <p rend="centered"><hi rend="underline">Military Alliance With Germany</hi></p>
               <p>On <date when-iso="1939-04-26">26th April</date> <persName>Ribbentrop</persName> wired <persName>Ambassador Ott</persName> that <persName>OSHIMA</persName> said that the time had come, in the opinion of the Japanese Army, to conclude a general defensive alliance among Germany, Italy and Japan; the Japanese Army's suggestion for the alliance included granting help and assistance in case one of the three powers should be attacked without provocation by another power; and that the discussions between Berline, Rome and Tokyo had for special reasons and in accordance with agreements made with the other partner been conducted outside usual diplomatic channels.</p>
               <pb n="519"/>
               <p><persName>Military Attache OSHIMA</persName> carried on negotiations for the alliance without consulting <persName>Ambassador TOGO</persName>.</p>
               <p><persName>OSHIMA</persName>, while Military Attache received a report of the decision of the Five Ministers' Conference on the draft proposal, transmitted it to <persName>Ribbentrop</persName>, and committed Japan against the policy of limiting Japan's military assistance to cases where Soviet Russia alone was involved.</p>
               <p>The Army put forward <persName>OSHIMA</persName>'s name for the German ambassadorship after <persName>TOGO</persName>'s transfer and the General Staff Headquarters repeatedly urged him to accept. His appointment was also urged by <persName>War Minister ITAGAKI</persName>. He accepted.</p>
               <p>Just after the formation of the <persName>HIRANUMA</persName> Cabinet in <date when-iso="1939-01">January 1939</date> <persName>OSHIMA</persName> was advised that <persName>Minister Ito</persName> and others would be dispatched to Berlin with instructions as to the Government's policy. <persName>OSHIMA</persName>'s request for advance information was denied and he was told to await the arrival of the Ito Commission.</p>
               <p>In <date when-iso="1939-02">February 1939</date>, prior to the arrival of the Ito Commission, <persName>OSHIMA</persName>, in an effort to establish his own views regarding the propriety of a Japanese-German alliance which would require Japan to participate in an European war if England became involved with Germany, made a tour of Europe to consult the Japanese Ambassadors.</p>
               <pb n="520"/>
               <p>The Ito Commission arrived in <location><placeName>Berlin</placeName></location> in <date when-iso="1939-02">February 1939</date> and advised <persName>OSHIMA</persName> of the Government's views regarding the proposed pact and directed him to carry on negotiations within those limits.</p>
               <p><persName>Ciano</persName> in his diary on <date when-iso="1939-03-08">8th March 1939</date>, stated that <persName>OSHIMA</persName> and <persName>SHIRATORI</persName> had refused to communicate through official channels the Japanese reply on the Tri-Partite alliance in which the intention was expressed of regarding the pact as exclusively anti-Russian. <persName>Ribbentrop</persName> in his memo to <persName>Ott</persName>  on <date when-iso="1939-04-26">26th April 1939</date> also stated that <persName>OSHIMA</persName> and <persName>SHIRATORI</persName> had refused to officially present to Germany and Italy the Japanese proposal to limit the mutual obligations of assistance to the case of a war with Russia.</p>
               <p><persName>OSHIMA</persName> cabled his views to Tokyo in opposition to the proposals. The Deputy Chief of Army General Staff told the Lord Keeper of the Privy Seal that he had "strictly warned <persName>Ambassador OSHIMA</persName> that the supreme authority of diplomacy is vested in the Emperor" and he cautioned <persName>OSHIMA</persName> that he should not forget his position by expressing as his own the opinions of Germany.</p>
               <p>Between the arrival of the Ito Commission and the Government's reply to <persName>OSHIMA</persName>'s objections <persName>OSHIMA</persName> and <persName>SHIRATORI</persName> continued to express disapproval of the Government's policy.</p>
               <pb n="521"/>
               <p>The Japanese Government about the end of March reconsidered its stand and forwarded new instructions to <persName>OSHIMA</persName> and <persName>SHIRATORI</persName> who branded the new proposals as "impossible" and refused to officially deliver the proposals to the German and Italian Governments.</p>
               <p rend="centered"><hi rend="underline">Threatens resignation as Ambassador</hi></p>
               <p>The Five Ministers' Conference of <date when-iso="1939-04-25">25th April 1939</date> considered an urgent request from <persName>OSHIMA</persName> and <persName>SHIRATORI</persName> for their recall.</p>
               <p>Not only did the threat of resignation serve to strengthen Germany and Italy in their positions with regard to the pact, but it served the purpose of wringing additional concessions from the Japanese Government to meet the views of <persName>Hitler</persName>, <persName>Ribbentrop</persName>, <persName>OSHIMA</persName> and <persName>SHIRATORI</persName>.</p>
               <p>The Five Ministers' Conference of <date when-iso="1939-04-25">25th April 1939</date> decided that communication be made directly by <persName>Premier HIRANUMA</persName> with <persName>Hitler</persName> and <persName>Mussolini</persName> through the German and Italian Ambassadors at <location><placeName>Tokyo</placeName></location>. This "<persName>HIRANUMA</persName> Declaration of <date when-iso="1939-05-04">4th May 1939</date>," provided that military assistance would be given against nations other than Russia "to the extent possible". <persName>OSHIMA</persName> testified that the message to <persName>Hitler</persName> was thus strongly in support of the line of negotiations which he was pursuing at that time.</p>
               <p>The reservations in the proposal brought by <pb n="522"/> the Ito Commission limited the obligation of war participation on the part of Japan to nations which had embraced Communism. These reservations were altered in the new proposals delivered to the Ambassadors during the latter part of March. <persName>Foreign Minister Arita</persName> reported to the Emperor on <date when-iso="1939-04-08">8th April 1939</date> that <persName>OSHIMA</persName> and <persName>SHIRATORI</persName> acted without regard to the wishes of the central authorities and overstepped their authority in replying to Germany and Italy that Japan intended to fight in the event of those two powers waging war against England and France. This was followed by a conference between the Emperor and <persName>War Minister ITAGAKI</persName>, in which the Emperor charged that the Ambassadors had infringed upon his supreme authority and he personally reprimanded <persName>ITAGAKI</persName> for supporting them.</p>
               <p><persName>Ribbentrop</persName>, after the receipt of the <persName>HIRANUMA</persName> declaration, asked <persName>OSHIMA</persName> whether Japan could be considered as being in a state of war in the event of Germany going to war against a third nation even if no military aid from Japan were given; to which <persName>OSHIMA</persName> replied in the affirmative. <persName>Foreign Minister Arita</persName> commented that it was inexcusable for <persName>OSHIMA</persName> on his own authority to make such an arbitrary reply; but <persName>HIRANUMA</persName> and <persName>ITAGAKI</persName> upheld <persName>OSHIMA</persName>'s answer.</p>
               <p><persName>OSHIMA</persName> disobeyed an order by the Japanese <pb n="523"/> Government to deliver a short protest to the Geman Government on the conclusion of the German-Russian Non-Aggression Pact. Notwithstanding this, <persName>OSHIMA</persName> told his Government he had followed its order. He delivered the protest unofficially on <date when-iso="1939-09-18">18th September 1939</date> when he congratulated Germany on the success of its Polish campaign.</p>
               <p><persName>OSHIMA</persName> returned to Japan in <date when-iso="1939-12">December 1939</date>. <persName>Ribbentrop</persName> advised <persName>Ott</persName> that <persName>Oshima</persName> on his return to Japan would work for German-Japanese friendship. <persName>Ribbentrop</persName> and <persName>OSHIMA</persName> agreed that Japan's position ultimately would be secured by German victories and that the idea of close cooperation between Germany, Italy and Japan was to the interest of all parties concerned.</p>
               <p rend="centered"><hi rend="underline">Working to Overthrow Cabinet</hi></p>
               <p>On <date when-iso="1939-12-31">31st December 1939</date>, <persName>Ambassador Ott</persName> reported that the coalition cabinet, for the time being, was not capable of complete affiliation with any of the European power groups; that according to the views of Ambassadors <persName>Oshima</persName> and <persName>SHIRATORI</persName> two or three more transient cabinets would be needed to bring about a drastic change, and that the two Ambassadors were working hard for the overthrow of the Cabinet.</p>
               <p><persName>Stahmer</persName>, <persName>Ribbentrop</persName>'s special envoy with the Duke of Coburg on his visit to Japan, interviewed <persName>OSHIMA</persName>, <persName>SHIRATORI</persName> and others and reported on <date when-iso="1940-02-23">23rd <pb n="524"/> February 1940</date> that they remained in an unchanged friendly attitude and were ready to give every support, and that means were being taken to strengthen pro-German influence in the Foreign Ministry and the Army.</p>
               <p>On <date when-iso="1940-06-12">12th June 1940</date>, <persName>Ambassador Ott</persName> wired his government that the Embassy was still endeavoring to stir up Japanese ill feeling against America by influencing the press and leading political personalities. <persName>Ott</persName> added, "In confidential cooperation with the Embassy, Ambassadors <persName>OSHIMA</persName> and <persName>SHIRATORI</persName> and circles closely connected with them are operating in the same direction."</p>
               <p>On <date when-iso="1940-07-08">8th July 1940</date>, <persName>Ribbentrop</persName> stated that he had for years furthered German-Japan cooperation with <persName>OSHIMA</persName> and that it had already borne fruit for both parties; that Japan had drawn considerable advantages throughout the whole period of her struggle for China from the existence of a strong Germany, and that without a restrengthened Germany Japan would not have been able to penetrate as deeply into English and other spheres of interest in East Asia as actually happened.</p>
               <p>When the Yonai Cabinet was succeeded by the Second Konoye Cabinet, both <persName>OSHIMA</persName> and <persName>SHIRATORI</persName>, in press interviews, approved <persName>MATSUOKA</persName>'s appointment as Foreign Minister.</p>
               <pb n="525"/>
               <p rend="centered"><hi rend="underline">Tripartite Pact Concluded</hi></p>
               <p>An Imperial Rescript was issued for the purpose of uniting the people behind the Tripartite Pact, which was signed on <date when-iso="1940-09-27">27th September 1940</date>.</p>
               <p><persName>OSHIMA</persName> in a conversation with <persName>Erdsmanndorff</persName> on <date when-iso="1941-10-18">18th October 1941</date> expressed his opinion that the Japanese Government must have been certain when the Tripartite Pact was concluded that the Greater East Asia Sphere could only be achieved through a push to the south, and with the sword at that.</p>
               <p><persName>OSHIMA</persName>'s article, entitled "Activate the Alliance--Shun Diplomatic Passivity" appeared on <date when-iso="1940-10-27">27th October 1940</date> in the Yomiuru newspaper. It stated that the Tripartite Alliance had as its object the founding of a New Order in East Asia and in Europe; and this could not be effected without military aggression, as it involved the territories and rights of sovereign nations. The article continued that the settlement of the China Incident and the European war should be considered as a unity and that the Japanese people must make up their minds that the treaty called for Japanese cooperation in establishing the New Order of Germany and Italy in Europe; it called upon the nation with unswerving resolution to make careful preparations to combat any obstructions which other nations might offer; it admonished the people to stand foursquare ready to burst through any barrier to the achievement of Japanese aims; it <pb n="526"/> reminded them that never before were such resolute determination and firm courage necessary; the treaty must be activated with all speed, and the first essential step to this was complete preparations; it asserted that the Tripartite powers must march ahead in perfect concord to protect their common interests.</p>
               <p>This article was followed by another in the <date when-iso="1940-11">November 1940</date> issue of the magazine Dai Asia Shugi, published by the Greater East Asia Association, picturing the war aims of Germany and Italy as being similar to Japan's and assigning that as the reason for conclusion of the alliance. It asserted that the fact that the alliance was concluded with the grand object of establishing a New Order in the world constituted the great feature of the treaty.</p>
               <p>On <date when-iso="1940-12-13">13th December 1940</date>, <persName>Ott</persName> wired <persName>Ribbentrop</persName> that the Foreign Minister had repeatedly offered the German ambassadorial post to <persName>OSHIMA</persName>, who declined in order to continue his politically active work for the Tripartite Pact. The Foreign Minister renewed pressure on <persName>OSHIMA</persName> to accept and important navy circles also urged him to accept, which he did.</p>
               <p>At a farewell party given to the new Ambassador <persName>MATSUOKA</persName> stated that Japan's efforts for the establishment of the new order in East Asia began with the Manchurian Incident, and that the Holy War in which Japan had been engaged in Asia for <pb n="527"/> three and one half years was <note>for</note> the purpose of establishing a New Order in East Asia. <persName>MATSUOKA</persName> pointed out that <persName>OSHIMA</persName> had built up such an absolute personal credit among the leaders of the German Government that he coudl talk with them without reserve, and spoke of the tremendous national reliance which was reposed in <persName>OSHIMA</persName> as the result of his new assignment.</p>
               <p>On <date when-iso="1941-02-10">10th February 1941</date> <persName>MATSUOKA</persName> informed Germany that he desired to discuss in Berlin such important questions as the attitude of the partners of the Tripartite Pact toward America, a preventive attack against Singapore, termination of the China conflict and the strengthening of Japanese hands in the negotiations with Russia as the result of a surprise agreement with <persName>Chiang Kai-shek</persName>.</p>
               <p rend="centered"><hi rend="underline">Attack on Britain Urged</hi></p>
               <p>In a conference with <persName>Weiszaecker</persName> on <date when-iso="1941-02-22">22nd February 1941</date>, <persName>OSHIMA</persName> suggested the possibility of a <hi rend="underline">modus vivendi</hi> with Russia which would be sufficient to "relieve Japan in the north". With regard to China, <persName>OSHIMA</persName> expressed the view that pressure would be put on <persName>Chiang Kai-shek</persName> through Japanese support of <persName>Wang Ching-wei</persName>. As to British possessions in East Asia, <persName>OSHIMA</persName> stated that it was necessary that Hong Kong be taken and then Singapore should be seized in grand style by operations from both the sea and the land. <persName>OSHIMA</persName> <pb n="528"/> told <persName>Weiszaecker</persName> that he had energetically advocated the point of view in Tokyo "that one should not let slip by opportunities that would determine the fate of Japan for centuries".</p>
               <p>The next day, <date when-iso="1941-02-23">23rd February 1941</date>, <persName>OSHIMA</persName> conferred with <persName>Ribbentrop</persName> and explained that preparations for the occupation of Singapore would be completed by the end of May and, for safety, preparations must be made not only for war against England but also against America. The moment for the occupation of Singapore, he said, must be co-ordinated with operations in Europe. Following these discussions  <persName>Ribbentrop</persName>, on <date when-iso="1941-02-27">27th February 1941</date>, wired <persName>Ambassador Ott</persName> in Tokyo directing him to work with all the means at his commmand to the end that Japan take possession of Singapore by surprise as soon as possible. On <date when-iso="1941-03-03">3rd March 1941</date> <persName>Hitler</persName> issued Directive #24 in which it was stated that the aim of the co-operation based on the Three Power Pact must be to bring Japan as soon as possible into active operations in the Far East.</p>
               <p><persName>Ambassador Ott</persName> in his report to <persName>Ribbentrop</persName> on <date when-iso="1941-03-25">25th March 1941</date> stated that upon inquiring from the Chief of the Navy General Staff, <persName>Admiral Kondo</persName>, he was told that the Navy was vigorously preparing for an attack upon Singapore and preparations were expected to be concluded by the end of May, and on inquiry from the Chief of the Army General Staff, <pb n="529"/> <persName>General Sugiyama</persName>, he had been advised that the Army was also making preparations for an attack. <persName>Ott</persName> reported that the will to attack existed in the Army and the Navy, that preparations for attack were in progress and that military prospects were favorable. <persName>Ott</persName> emphasized that the need for the Japanese rear to be left free by Russia played a decisive part in the Japanese considerations and was being striven for by reconciliation with Russia.</p>
               <p>Meanwhile <persName>Hitler</persName>'s plan to attack the U.S.S.R. had been decided upon, and it had become imperative that a Japanese threat be maintained against Russia in the East. Consequently, Ribbentrop discouraged a non-aggression pact between Japan and Russia. He advised <persName>MATUSOKA</persName> that it would probably be best in view of the whole situation not to carry the discussion with the Russians too far and that in his opinion the question should be dealt with only in a purely formal way and should not be gone into deeply.</p>
               <p><persName>OSHIMA</persName> learned from <persName>Hitler</persName> or <persName>Ribbentrop</persName> the probability of a German attack on Russia. In the light of this changed situation <persName>OSHIMA</persName> was of the opinion that Japan should not be too hasty in entering into a non-aggression pact with Russia, and he advised <persName>MATSUOKA</persName> accordingly.</p>
               <p rend="centered"><hi rend="underline">American Negotiations Offered</hi></p>
               <p>The proposal of <persName>MATSUOKA</persName> to make a trip to the United States appeared in the press and <persName>OSHIMA</persName> <pb n="530"/> immediately undertook to obstruct the course of the American-Japanese negotiation. On <date when-iso="1941-05-03">3rd May</date>, his Military Attache <persName><note>BANZAI</note></persName> sent a telegram to the General Staff, in which he pointed out that the proposed trip by <persName>MATSUOKA</persName> would create a very unfavorable situation and nullify the results of <persName>MATSUOKA</persName>'s visit to Germany and Italy, and he gave warning that the probelm of <persName>OSHIMA</persName>'s resignation might arise, thereby causing a fiasco in the basic problems of Japan's foreign diplomacy. <persName>BANZAI</persName> requested grave deliberation on the matter. This telegram was delivered by the General Staff to the Foreign Ministry where it was shown to have been received on <date when-iso="1941-05-04">5th May</date>. <persName>OSHIMA</persName> wired the Foreign Minister on <date when-iso="1941-05-04">4th May</date> advising that although the German Government had given no expression of its attitude, he was nevertheless greatly concerned over the proposed trip and he reminded <persName>MATSUOKA</persName> that it was only common sense to consider the United States completely hostile to Germany and Italy.</p>
               <p>In the first of three telegrams to <persName>MATSUOKA</persName> on <date when-iso="1941-05-20">20th May 1941</date> <persName>OSHIMA</persName> expressed deep concern over the development of negotiations with America and its effect upon the future of Japan as well as the Tripartite Pact.</p>
               <p>In the second telegram, he stated he had answered <persName>Ribbentrop</persName>'s criticisms by stating that Japan was observing the Tripartite Pact as the <pb n="531"/> basis of its diplomacy, and accordingly there was no reason to conclude the proposed treaty between Japan and America contrary to the Tripartite Pact. He prophesied that if the proposed agreement should be concluded Japan would lose the chance to establish her right of leadership in East Asia. <persName>OSHIMA</persName> then presented <persName>MATSUOKA</persName> with two plans which, without the authority of the Foreign Office, he had discussed with <persName>Ribbentrop</persName>. The first was to refuse the proposal of America, and the second was that, if the agreement were concluded, it be done on condition that American maintain a neutral attitude without extending convoy patrol assistance.</p>
               <p>In the third telegram <persName>OSHIMA</persName> repeated the deep dissatisfaction of the German Government with the American-Japanese negotiations and the concern of the German Government about the future of the Tripartite Pact. He reminded <persName>MATSUOKA</persName> that the European War was developing very favorably for Germany and Italy and that very important developments were expected in the light of which it was unreasonable for Japan to lose the confidence and trust of Germany and Italy who would become the leaders in Europe. <persName>OSHIMA</persName> expressed his fear that such a two-faced diplomacy should lead Japan to an absolute international isolation during the critical period which might arise after the war. He gave warning that if Japan solved the China Incident with the support of America, she would lose the opportunity to <pb n="532"/> expand southward and the possibility of attacking Singapore. He emphasized that such a treaty would permit the United States to reinforce her assistance to Britain which would greatly affect the war in Europe. Should Japan abandon her right to leadership in the southern regions for the sake of America, it was clear, he stated, that Japan could not stress her leadership to Germany and Italy and this would mean abandonment by Japan of her great mission to establish a New Order in the Greater East Asia. He earnestly implored <persName>MATSUOKA</persName> that if the conclusion of the agreement was unavoidable, the Japanese Government should at least uphold the principle that Japan would facilitate the battle of Germany and Italy against Britain, that Japan should demand America's neutrality in the European war, and that it should be made clear that Japan had an obligation based upon the Tripartite Pact to participate in the war.</p>
               <p><persName>Admiral Yokoi</persName>, a member of the Military Commission in Berlin, stated that the reason why the joint Military Commission under the Tripartite Pact did not function effectively was that an unofficial commission consisting of <persName>Ribbentrop</persName> and <persName>OSHIMA</persName> was established. <persName>Ribbentrop</persName> and <persName>OSHIMA</persName>, he said, conferred in respect to military measures, and with these conferences proceeding on the level of the German Foreign Office, it was difficult for <pb n="533"/> the Military Commission to function.</p>
               <p>In a conference with <persName>Hitler</persName> on <date when-iso="1942-01-03">3rd January 1942</date>, <persName>OSHIMA</persName> advised that he was empowered by his Government to discuss the prosecution of the war with the Reich Foreign Minister. Even though individual questions could be discussed directly between the Army, the air force, and the Navy, it was  of the greatest importance that the main line of policy should be laid down exclusively by him and the Foreign Minister. The same was true for economic and political questions.</p>
               <p rend="centered"><hi rend="underline">Economic Domination Of The World</hi></p>
               <p><persName>OSHIMA</persName> and <persName>Ribbentrop</persName> on <date when-iso="1942-03-23">23rd March 1942</date> discussed future economic cooperation between the Europe-Africa sphere under the leadership of the Axis and the Greater East Asia sphere under the leadership of Japan, in which the goal was a large-scale economic agreement with preference for the Tripartite powers and with the exclusion as far as possible of third parties, American in particular. <persName>OSHIMA</persName> had previously pointed out to <persName>Ribbentrop</persName> that the development and utilization of "the raw materials-rich South Sea regions" went hand-in-hand with the progress of military operations, and that Japan was doing its utmost to facilitate the delivery of East Asiatic products to Germany. Germany, he stated, should do everything to deliver machines, munitions, materials and plants to Japan.</p>
               <pb n="534"/>
               <p>On <date when-iso="1942-05-09">9th May 1942</date> <persName>Ribbentrop</persName> pointed out that the starting point for all political and all economic discussions and plans was the Tripartite Pact, which would prove effective for all international settlements even after teh war and for an enormous length of time to come. The two major political areas created by the Tripartite Pact, he said, must in advance fix their economic relations in such a way that they would in no way adversely effect the political relations. <persName>OSHIMA</persName> concurred in the idea of a treaty arrangement for economic relations and stated that it was all the more important because it would be difficult to bring America to its knees in the present war and that after the end of the war battle would have to be waged with the United States in the field of economy through an economic boycott by Japan and the Axis. <persName>Ribbentrop</persName> proposed the forumulation of a basic accord, which would be for publication, which would include important details on which <persName>OSHIMA</persName> expressed his fundamental agreement. The various points on which <persName>Ribbentrop</persName> and <persName>OSHIMA</persName> fundamentally agreed formed the charter for projecting world domination and control into the far distant future and were covered by the following proposals:</p>
               <p>(1) Economic cooperation between the two great spheres under the pact should be <pb n="535"/> facilitated by a strict central control.</p>
               <p>(2) The guiding powers from their natural economic predominance should exert influence on the regulation of economy of the independent states within the two spheres, thereby necessitating that these independent states carry out far-reaching control of their economies. This it was expected would finally result in the two economic areas being combined into one unit which would also affect the field of customs and currency.</p>
               <p>(3) The Tripartite powers should be given mutual preference in all economic fields. This contemplated preferential tariffs, action to prevent the products of one partner from being forced from the market by an outsider, such as the United States, and the restriction of sale of important goods to third powers until after the needs of the partners had been met.</p>
               <p>(4) The resumption and continuation of economic relations with enemy countries after the war should take place only after mutual agreement between the partners. This was to apply particularly against the United States and Central and South American countries</p>
               <p>(5) In the event of economically independent establishments within the two economic areas, such as the Mitsui interests in Japan, opposing the contemplated economic control, measures should be taken to eliminate them.</p>
               <pb n="536"/>
               <p>These negotiations led to a trade agreement in <date when-iso="1943-01">January 1943</date> between Japan and Germany and an identical agreement between Japan and Italy. This was the treaty which <persName>Ribbentrop</persName> and <persName>OSHIMA</persName> agreed in their <date when-iso="1943-05-09">9th May</date> conference should be formulated for publication. What they secretly agreed to for the purpose of bringing the entire world under the domination and control of the Axis Powers was set forth in a secret protocol.</p>
               <p><hi rend="underline">A Greater East Asia By Armed Force</hi></p>
               <p>In <date when-iso="1939-09">September 1939</date>, <persName>OSHIMA</persName>, after Germany attacked Poland, advised military aggression in the southern areas of Greater East Asia and against Hongkong for which the Japanese Navy, he said, was prepared. He thought Japan should try to tear the Netherlands from England to exploit the raw materials of the East Indies. In his article, enttitled "Activate the Alliance--Shun Diplomatic Passivity," published in <date when-iso="1940-10">October 1940</date>, he said that prior to the Tripartite Pact, Japan for a long time had been determined to carry out its mission to set up a New Order in Greater East Asia. He thought that the Japanese Government had in mind when it made the Tripartite Pact that the Greater East Asia sphere could not be achieved without a push to the south by the use of armed force.</p>
               <p>At the time of the Japanese mediation of the <pb n="537"/> Indo-China-Thailand border dispute, <persName>OSHIMA</persName> said a decision was reached, for an agreement with the Thailand Government for a Japanese invasion of Thailand, to secure bases as a springboard against Singapore.</p>
               <p>On <date when-iso="1941-06-10">10th June 1941</date>, <!-- "Name" in  <persName> tag should be capitalized dmg --> <persname>OSHIMA</persname> advised Germany that the Japanese Army desired to obtain bases for the Navy in southern French Indo-China, for a favorable strategic position vis-a-vis Singapore. This was followed on <date when-iso="1941-07-12">12th July 1941</date> by <persName>OSHIMA</persName>'s statement to <persName>Weiszsacker</persName> that the occupation of certain positions in southern Indo-China as bases for aircraft and warships was an urgent Japanese need. <persName>OSHIMA</persName> further stated on this occasion that although he did not consider a move toward south Indo-China imminent, he thought that Japan was waiting for a good opportunity. On <date when-iso="1941-07-17">17th July 1941</date>, <persName>OSHIMA</persName> advised <persName>Ribbentrop</persName> that the Japanese Government had started negotiations with the French Government to secure naval and air bases in Indo-China; the realization of this was the first step in Japan's push to the south. He said this would divert English-American forces and give aid to Germany and Italy in the spirit of the Tripartite Pact. <persName>OSHIMA</persName> then called upon Germany to assist Japan in its negotiations with France.</p>
                <p>On <date when-iso="1941-11-17">17th November 1941</date>, <persName>Erdmannsdorff</persName> conferred with <!-- Name in <persName> tag should be capitalized dmg --> <persname>OSHIMA</persname> at the direction of <pb n="538"/> <persName>Ribbentrop</persName>, to inquire whether the Japanese advance would be to the north or to the south. <persName>OSHIMA</persName> advised him that on advance by Japan toward the south was, in his opinion, unavoidable because of the pressing Japanese need for petroleum, and in explaining what was meant by advance to the south he stated that the seizure of the island of Borneo was above all necessary. <persName>OSHIMA</persName> expressed the need for increasing the number of Japanese troops in south Indo-China for an invasion of Thailand, to obtain a springboard against Singapore.</p>
               <p rend="centered"><hi rend="underline">Attack on U.S.S.R. Revealed</hi></p>
               <p>After Germany attacked Russia, <persName>OSHIMA</persName> insisted upon an early Japanese action against Russia. The German attack took place on <date when-iso="1941-06-22">22nd June 1941</date>. On <date when-iso="1941-06-28">28th June</date>, <persName>Ribbentrop</persName> cabled to <persName>Ambassador Ott</persName> in <location><placeName>Tokyo</placeName></location> that he had reached an agreement with <persName>OSHIMA</persName> that the latter would influence his government to speedy military action against Russia. In a telegram of the same date <persName>Ott</persName> advised <persName>Ribbentrop</persName> that, according to confidential reports coming from the Japanese Foreign Office, <persName>OSHIMA</persName> urgently advised the Japanese Government to attack Russia soon.</p>
               <p>In <date when-iso="1941-10">October 1941</date>, <persName>OSHIMA</persName> replied to a remark by <persName>Erdmannsdorff</persName> regarding the appearance of new Russian divisions from Siberia on the German front <pb n="539"/> that it would be good if the Japanese Army by means of a push into <location><placeName>east Siberia</placeName></location> contributed to the restoration of a land connection between Germany and Japan, that he had often submitted proposals to that effect to his government and that he hoped that action in accordance therewith would soon be taken.</p>
               <p><persName>OSHIMA</persName> stated in a conference with <persName>Ribbentrop</persName> on <date when-iso="1942-03-23">23rd March 1942</date> that although he had received no official communication of the Japanese intentions he agreed with <persName>Ribbentrop</persName> that an advance against <location><placeName>Vladivostok</placeName></location> and in the direction of <!-- Lake Baikal should be in <placeName> tag dmg--><location>Lake Baikal</location> would be of special significance and that he would do everything to have his government undertake the advance that year.</p>
               <p>In a memorandum to <persName>Ribbentrop</persName> dated <date when-iso="1942-04-21">21st April 1942</date>, <persName>Weiszaecker</persName> reported that <persName>OSHIMA</persName> stated it seemed to him that Japan should attack the Russians in East Asia and assured <persName>Weiszaecker</persName> that he was working hard to put an end to the wholly unnatural situation in which Japan was still living in peace with the Russian enemy so furiously engaged by Germany.</p>
               <p>It appears from a memorandum of a conference between <persName>Ribbentrop</persName> and <persName>OSHIMA</persName> on <date when-iso="1942-07-09">9th July 1942</date>, that <persName>Ribbentrop</persName> suggested the advisability of a Japanese attack on Russia, and <persName>OSHIMA</persName> stated that he was convinced of the imperativeness of <pb n="540"/> such attack and promised to report immediately to Tokyo.</p>
               <p>When <persName>OSHIMA</persName> transmitted <persName>Ribbentrop</persName>'s suggestion, he added his own point of view that "an early advance against Russia and intensive action to paralyze English shipping in the Indian Ocean was proper."</p>
               <p>On <date when-iso="1942-07-30">30th July 1942</date>, in conveying the Japanese reply--namely, that under the circumstances action by Japan against the Soviet Union would bring about too great a dispersion of Japan's strength--he added that personally he shared the understanding that an uniquely favorable opportunity presented itself to Japan to deal a blow to the Russians, and that he was for conducting a thrust against Russia in spite of the necessity of operations in the southern theatre.</p>
               <p>In a conversation on <date when-iso="1943-04-18">18th April 1943</date>, <persName>OSHIMA</persName> assured <persName>Ribbentrop</persName> that Japan would certainly attack Russia if success could be expected and that he understood that for the last twenty years the General Staff had worked out plans for an attack on Russia. In a conference in <date when-iso="1944-09">September 1944</date> in which <persName>Hitler</persName> held out the hope that he would again go on the offensive against the Red Army, <persName>OSHIMA</persName> assured him that Japan would fight on the side of <pb n="541"/> Germany until final victory had been achieved, and that it would use its last troops to realize this as there was only one road for Japan which it would follow to the end.</p>
               <p><hi rend="underline">Joint Operations Of Axis Powers - No Separate Peace</hi></p>
               <p><persName>OSHIMA</persName> in a telegram of <date when-iso="1941-11">November 1941</date> quoted <persName>Ribbentrop</persName> as saying: "Should Japan become engaged in a war against the United States, Germany, of course, would join the war immediately. There is absolutely no possibility of Germany's entering into a separate peace with the United States under such circumstances. The Fuehrer is determined on that point." He requested that a copy of the telegram be shown to the Army and Navy authorities in Tokyo. Notwithstanding the receipt of this word from <persName>Ribbentrop</persName>, <persName>OSHIMA</persName> was directed to confer with <persName>Hitler</persName> also. On <date when-iso="1941-12-05">5th December</date> <persName>Ribbentrop</persName> submitted for hurried action to Mussolini a plan for triple action on Japanese intervention in the war and a pledge not to make a separate peace. On <date when-iso="1941-12-13">13th December 1941</date>, the obligations of the Tripartite Pact were recognized by the conclusion of a treaty in which the three powers agreed to wage war in common against the United States, promised not to lay down arms until the common war was successfully concluded, and pledged that they would not conclude an armistice or peace with either the United States or the British Empire without a complete understanding between themselves. <pb n="542"/> On <date when-iso="1941-12-14">14th December 1941</date>, <persName>Hitler</persName> gave a reception in <persName>OSHIMA</persName>'s honor, at which he presented him with the Grand Cross of the Order of Merit of the German Eagle in gold in recognition of his services in the achievement of German-Japanese cooperation which had finally culminated in a close brotherhood of arms. <persName>OSHIMA</persName> expressed his delight that this brotherhood fo arms had come into fruition.</p>
               <p><persName>OSHIMA</persName> later delivered a comprehensive lecture at <persName>Hitler</persName>'s reception on the war situation in the Pacifc and in the Archipelago area. <persName>OSHIMA</persName> informed <persName>Hitler</persName> that landing warfare had been greatly developed and practiced in Japan during the past thirty years and that exercises in this type of warfare had been carried out with great energy on the island of <location><!-- <placeName> tag is missing a "c" in place dmg --><plaeName>Hainan</plaeName></location>.</p>
               <p>On <date when-iso="1942-01-18">18th January 1942</date> the military agreement was concluded by which the world was divided into zones for operational cooperation between the Axis powers. The agreement also provided for collaboration in the planning and conducting of economic warfare and in psychological warfare. In starting negotiations for economic cooperation in a conference with <persName>Ribbentrop</persName> on <date when-iso="1942-01-02">2nd January 1942</date>, <persName>OSHIMA</persName> stated that these negotiations should be parallel to the conversations with military cooperation then under way.</p>
               <p>On <date when-iso="1941-02-23">23rd February 1941</date> <persName>OSHIMA</persName> advised <persName>Ribbentrop</persName> <pb n="543"/> that he intended to set up a program with German representatives for the intensification of Japanese propaganda and establish a newspaper division within the Japanese Embassy. Cooperation in the use of the propaganda weapon was directed especially toward India and Arabian countries. In Directive No. 24, which, as has been shown, followed closely <persName>OSHIMA</persName>'s conference with <persName>Ribbentrop</persName> on <date when-iso="1941-02-23">23rd February 1941</date>, <persName>Hitler</persName> emphasized the necessity of strengthening the Japanese war potential and directed the high commands of the branches of the armed forces to meet in a comprehensive and generous way the demands of the Japanese concerning communication of German warfare adn combat experiences and to assist in matters of war economy and technique. On <date when-iso="1941-03-29">29th March 1941</date> <persName>Ribbentrop</persName> told <persName>MATSUOKA</persName> that he had discussed with <persName>OSHIMA</persName> the question of German assistance in the blow against Singapore and offered <persName>MATSUOKA</persName> the advice of German experts on aerial warfare regarding the use of dive bombers against the British fleet in <location><placeName>Singapore</placeName></location>.</p>

                

            </div>


            <div type="notes">

                <!-- and so on -->




                <!-- common tags you'll likely be using, with definitions. Feel free to add if you find yourself using a tag frequently -->

                <!-- date. Note that dates must be contained within paragraphs -->
                <p><date when-iso="2020-02-29">date</date></p>


                <!-- Deleted or crossed out text -->
                <p><del>this text is deleted</del>this text is not</p>
                <!-- Location. Use for place names -->
                <p><location>
                        <placeName>Placename</placeName>
                    </location></p>

                <!-- highlighting use this for any means of highlighting text. Renditions include underlining, italics, all caps ect  -->
                <p><hi rend="underline"/></p>
                <!-- name. Use for named individuals -->
                <p><name>name here</name></p>
                <!-- use for notes written on the text -->
                <note hand="If handwriting is identifiably one persons">handwritten note on the
                    text</note>
                    <!-- <unclear reason="illegible"></unclear>. If you have a pretty strong guess as to what the word is based on context, you can supply it in the tag, but if it's just unreadable go ahead and leave it without content.-->
                <!-- paragaph -->
                <p>Text goes here</p>
                <!-- Page Break -->
                <pb n="pagenumber"/>
                <!-- Space use for significant space in text -->
                <space/>
            </div>
        </body>
    </text>
</TEI>
